<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Events on Open Source Club</title><link>/events/</link><description>Recent content in Events on Open Source Club</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Writing Well Behaved Command Line Applications</title><link>/events/2019-04-11-writing-well-behaved-command-line-applications-in-python/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2019-04-11-writing-well-behaved-command-line-applications-in-python/</guid><description>Commands that work together form the basis of *nix systems. You can take advantage of existing tools by making your own work well with others.
In this Talk we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss:
What makes a command line application &amp;ldquo;well-behaved&amp;rdquo; Why you might want to use Python (and when you might not) How you can use the click package to make your own CLIs Demos and a tutorial are available for those that want to try it for themselves.</description></item><item><title>Operator: The Well Rounded Hacker</title><link>/events/2019-04-04-operator-the-well-rounded-hacker/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2019-04-04-operator-the-well-rounded-hacker/</guid><description>The need for understanding complex technologies has never been greater—and never more poorly understood. Hiring managers often look for buzzphrase-compliant resumes that enumerate technologies and techniques. Technology users and integrators routinely use their tools to solve the wrong problems, leaving themselves bewildered by their surroundings. In a world where everyone is connected, this creates systemic vulnerability.
The computer expert firm Interhack was formed as a research group in 1997 and incorporated in 2000, helping people to stay in control of the technology, managing function, risk, and expense, as well as understanding the implications of technology and data in legal proceedings.</description></item><item><title>An Intermediate Introduction to Ansible</title><link>/events/2019-02-21-ansible/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2019-02-21-ansible/</guid><description>This week, we&amp;rsquo;ll be talking about Ansible. Owned by RedHat, Ansible is used in industry for tasks such as configuration management or keeping servers synchronized with standardized settings. In the age of disposible systems (containers and virtual machines) configuration management tools such as Ansible are indispensible. What differentiates Ansible from other CM tools such as Puppet or Chef is that Ansible is agentless, and able to communicate to any device over regular old SSH!</description></item><item><title>An Introduction to WebAssembly</title><link>/events/2019-02-07-webassembly/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2019-02-07-webassembly/</guid><description>Want to write a web application? Better get familiar with JavaScript! JavaScript has long been the king of front-end. While there have been various attempts to dethrone it, they have typically involved treating JavaScript as an assembly-language analog that you transpile your code to. This has lead to complex build pipelines that result in JavaScript which the browser has to parse and you still have to debug. But what if there were an actual byte-code language you could compile your non-JavaScript code to instead?</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Serverless Computing with AWS Lambda</title><link>/events/2019-01-31-serverless/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2019-01-31-serverless/</guid><description>Serverless computing is a hot topic. Serverless computing offers a unique blend of cost effectiveness, scalability, and simplicity which is why many startups and technology companies are starting to use serverless computing for their most demanding workloads. We&amp;rsquo;ll cover some background of serverless architecture, as well as walk through an example serverless application.
As always, laptops are encouraged and pizza will be provided.</description></item><item><title>How Arista Networks grew from $0 -$1+ billion using Open Source Principles</title><link>/events/2019-01-17-arista-networks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2019-01-17-arista-networks/</guid><description>Learn how Arista grew from a startup to a $1+ billion company supporting the largest cloud environments in the world. Arista Networks was founded to pioneer and deliver software-driven cloud networking solutions for large data center storage and computing environments. Arista EOS, is the most advanced network operating system to enable open third party development. The award-winning software is built upon a stable, open source Linux core with a central state-oriented database that makes EOS inherently self-healing, in-service upgradeable and extremely robust.</description></item><item><title>Big Data</title><link>/events/2018-11-29-big-data/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2018-11-29-big-data/</guid><description>During the second talk of this academic year by DK Panda, we will focus on the High-Performance Big Data (HiBD) project. As a part of this project, high-performance designs of many Bid Data Analytics software stacks such as Spark, Hadoop, HBase, Memcached, and Kafka has been designed. We will discuss about these software stacks and their architectures and features. Next, we will present the challenges in acceslerating these software stacks for modern supercomputers with multi-core processors, GPUs, and high-performance interconnects.</description></item><item><title>Bedrock Linux</title><link>/events/2018-11-15-bedrock-linux/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2018-11-15-bedrock-linux/</guid><description>Daniel paradigm Thau will present Bedrock Linux, a Linux distribution composed of software from other, typically mutually exclusive distributions.
If one would like a rock-solid stable base (for example, from Debian or a RHEL clone) yet still have easy access to cutting-edge packages (from, say, Arch Linux), automate compiling packages with Gentoo’s portage, and ensure that software aimed only for the ever popular Ubuntu will run smoothly - all at the same time, in the same distribution - Bedrock Linux provides a means to achieve this.</description></item><item><title>WordPress</title><link>/events/2018-11-08-wordpress/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2018-11-08-wordpress/</guid><description>This week we&amp;rsquo;ll have Ben Keith come in to give a talk!
Ben Keith will talk about WordPress, the open-source content management system. He&amp;rsquo;ll discuss and demonstrate some of the CMS&amp;rsquo;s many features, the WordPress command-line utility, and the workflows of theme and plugin development.
Ben works at the Institute for Nonprofit News on the Labs team as lead developer, building WordPress plugins and themes. He graduated from the Ohio State University&amp;rsquo;s College of Food, Agriculture, and Environmental Sciences in 2014 with a Bachelor of Science in Agriculture, majoring in agricultural communication and minoring in plant pathology.</description></item><item><title>Flatpak &amp; The Benefits of Sandboxing for Development</title><link>/events/2018-10-25-flatpak/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2018-10-25-flatpak/</guid><description>This week Chris be presenting a talk called &amp;ldquo;Flatpak &amp;amp; The Benefits Of Sandboxing For Development&amp;rdquo;. He&amp;rsquo;ll be giving a basic overview of application packaging, the flatpak sandbox, and will showcase how projects like GNOME use flatpak as a part of the development process.
As always, laptops are encouraged and pizza will be provided.</description></item><item><title>Hacking Home Automation with Software-Defined Radio</title><link>/events/2018-10-18-home-automation-with-software-defined-radio/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2018-10-18-home-automation-with-software-defined-radio/</guid><description>Ever thought about designing your own smart home? In this talk, we&amp;rsquo;ll focus on practical applications of replay attacks on off-the-shelf home automation devices, allowing them to be controlled with a Raspberry Pi. On the way, we&amp;rsquo;ll delve into how these devices transmit data over the air and how we can intercept and replay these transmissions using only a $20 RTL-SDR dongle, a Raspberry Pi, and free and open source software packages.</description></item><item><title>Linuxfest</title><link>/events/2018-10-12-linuxfest/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2018-10-12-linuxfest/</guid><description>This year, the sixteenth annual Ohio LinuxFest is being held October 12 - 13, 2018 at the Hyatt Regency in Columbus, Ohio. Ohio LinuxFest is the oldest and largest Linux and Open Source conference in the Midwest. In 2017, over 800 people attended LinuxFest from all over the country to learn about open source software as well as to visit our vendor booths and engage with our partners.
The Open Source Club mans a booth for the duration of the conference.</description></item><item><title>A Quick Guide to Contracts</title><link>/events/2018-10-04-guide-to-contracts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2018-10-04-guide-to-contracts/</guid><description>Contracts are an important part of business and they come in many shapes and sizes. As many people may be interested in taking up freelance work now or in the future, this week I will be covering the types of contracts that exist, the contract life cycle, and contracts in the software development world. I will also be covering some of the open source licenses that are out there and I will touch briefly on what licenses you should use in your projects!</description></item><item><title>Trends in Open Source</title><link>/events/2018-09-27-capital-one/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2018-09-27-capital-one/</guid><description>This week we will be having Capital One in to talk about trends in open source software!
It is also worth mentioning Capital One is offering an internship program and a career development program for recent graduates. The links are below:
Technology Internship Program (TIP) Technology Development Program (TDP) As always, laptops are encouraged and pizza will be provided.</description></item><item><title>Open Source Web Tools</title><link>/events/2018-09-20-cover-my-meds/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2018-09-20-cover-my-meds/</guid><description>This week at the Open Source Club we will be having a developer and some recruiters in from CoverMyMeds in to talk about a day in the life of a developer at CoverMyMeds and some of the open source web tools they use in their development cycle. They will be coming in with their recruiters and this would be a great opportunity to talk with them about their Co-Op Program they offer to students.</description></item><item><title>High-Performance Computing</title><link>/events/2018-09-13-high-performance-computing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2018-09-13-high-performance-computing/</guid><description>Significant growth has been witnessed during the last decade in High-Performance Computing (HPC) clusters with multi-/many-core processors, accelerators, and high-performance interconnects (such as InfiniBand, Omni-Path, iWARP, and RoCE). Many supercomputers in the world are currently being designed with commodity HPC clusters. The Network-Based Computing Laboratory at OSU/CSE in actively engaged in designing software libraries (HPC, Big Data, Deep Learning, and Cloud) for such supercomputers.
During this talk we will focus on the open-source MVAPICH software project.</description></item><item><title>Docker</title><link>/events/2018-09-06-docker/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2018-09-06-docker/</guid><description>By now, you&amp;rsquo;ve surely heard of the containerization sensation that&amp;rsquo;s sweeping the developer nation: Docker! Docker is a powerful tool that utilizes features of the Linux kernel to package applications in portable &amp;ldquo;images&amp;rdquo; and run them isolated from the host OS. In theory, an application should run just the same in production as it does in development—eliminating the &amp;ldquo;works on my machine&amp;rdquo; class of issue. In my talk, I will cover the basics of how to get up and running with Docker, how we use it at CoverMyMeds, as well as some of the issues we&amp;rsquo;ve encountered.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to the CLI</title><link>/events/2018-08-30-introduction-to-the-cli/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2018-08-30-introduction-to-the-cli/</guid><description>This week&amp;rsquo;s meeting will be an introduction to the command line. We recommend having a Linux distribution installed or having one in a VM so you can follow along.
As always, laptops are encouraged and pizza will be provided. At the end of the meeting, many of you requested that I put up the list of commands that I was working off of throughout the meeting. Below is a copy of the notes that I was working off of.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Open Source</title><link>/events/2018-08-23-introduction-to-open-source/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2018-08-23-introduction-to-open-source/</guid><description>This week we will be having our first meeting of the year, where we go over - in detail - &amp;ldquo;What is Open Source&amp;rdquo;.
As always, laptops are encouraged and pizza will be provided.</description></item><item><title>Python, Snippets from the Wild</title><link>/events/2018-04-19-python-snippets-from-the-wild/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2018-04-19-python-snippets-from-the-wild/</guid><description>This week smacz will presenting a talk called &amp;ldquo;Python: Snippets from the Wild&amp;rdquo;, where he goes over several snippets of his Python code that are running in production today. This is meant to spur discussion both about the implementation, and in what context the code is being used.
This is also the last meeting of the semester! There will be a brief and informal retrospective on the year, and a discussion on what to expect over the summer and in the semesters to come.</description></item><item><title>Reclaim Your Privacy</title><link>/events/2018-04-12-reclaim-your-privacy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2018-04-12-reclaim-your-privacy/</guid><description>This week, Christopher brainblasted Davis will be giving a talk on how to reclaim your privacy with free software on the internet.
As always, laptops are encouraged and pizza will be provided.</description></item><item><title>Crypto War II</title><link>/events/2018-04-05-crypto-war-ii/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2018-04-05-crypto-war-ii/</guid><description>This week Matt Curtin from Interhack is coming in to talk on Crypto War II. There are many forces in this world that are concerned and/or interested in the control of cryptography. We&amp;rsquo;re now entering into a second stage of the Crypto Wars, one that could prove much more dangerous to us all.
As always, laptops are encouraged and pizza will be provided.</description></item><item><title>Open Source Software in Journalism</title><link>/events/2018-03-29-open-source-software-in-journalism/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2018-03-29-open-source-software-in-journalism/</guid><description>This week&amp;rsquo;s talk is from Open Source Club and Lantern alumnus Ben Keith about open source software in journalism. Topics covered will include notable newsroom teams working in the open, tools available for anyone to use, conferences and training available, and some story ideas from the conference. This talk will include a partial recap of the 2018 Computer Assisted Reporting conference. This talk is suitable for all audiences, and journalism students are particularly encouraged to come.</description></item><item><title>OpenNMS</title><link>/events/2018-03-22-opennms/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2018-03-22-opennms/</guid><description>This week Tarus Balog, lead maintainer on OpenNMS is coming in to town to give a talk. OpenNMS is a FOSS network monitoring &amp;amp; management tool, licensed under the AGPLv3.
As always, laptops are encouraged and pizza will be provided.</description></item><item><title>Stuff I Learned in College That I Actually Use</title><link>/events/2018-03-08-how-to-succeed-in-college/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2018-03-08-how-to-succeed-in-college/</guid><description>How many times have you sat in a lecture and wondered to yourself &amp;ldquo;When will I ever use this?&amp;rdquo; In some cases, you are fully justified in doubting your studies. However, in many other cases what you are learning will be useful in ways you might not expect (coughtechnical interviewscough). In my talk, I aim to help you sort the diamonds from the rough and suggest which textbooks you can burn and which you may want to keep around.</description></item><item><title>Free Software</title><link>/events/2018-03-01-free-software/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2018-03-01-free-software/</guid><description>This week, Chris will be giving a talk on free software, and how using it can help you protect your privacy.
As always, laptops are encouraged and pizza will be provided.</description></item><item><title>ledger-cli</title><link>/events/2018-02-22-ledger-cli/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2018-02-22-ledger-cli/</guid><description>This week, Daniel paradigm Thau will be presenting ledger-cli [1], a command line double-entry accounting system. Ledger-cli&amp;rsquo;s file format is both human and machine readable, suitable for manipulation with UNIX utilities and tracking in version control. Ledger-cli is useful not only for traditional currencies and stocks, but also cryptocurrencies and abstract &amp;ldquo;commodities&amp;rdquo; such as PTO days. No accounting background will be necessary to follow the presentation.
As always, laptops are encouraged and pizza will be provided.</description></item><item><title>Citizenfour</title><link>/events/2018-02-15-citizenfour/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2018-02-15-citizenfour/</guid><description>This week, in lieu of a presentation, we will be viewing the documentary &amp;ldquo;Citizenfour&amp;rdquo; (2014).
Citizenfour is a 2014 documentary film directed by Laura Poitras, concerning Edward Snowden and the NSA spying scandal. The film had its US premiere on October 10, 2014, at the New York Film Festival and its UK premiere on October 17, 2014, at the BFI London Film Festival. The film features Snowden and Glenn Greenwald, and was co-produced by Poitras, Mathilde Bonnefoy, and Dirk Wilutzky, with Steven Soderbergh and others serving as executive producers.</description></item><item><title>Open Source, Code Cowboys, and Properly Testing Open-Source Applications</title><link>/events/2018-02-08-graycore/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2018-02-08-graycore/</guid><description>This week, we have a local company coming in: Graycore! Their presentation is titled &amp;ldquo;Open Source, Code Cowboys, and properly testing open-source applications&amp;rdquo;. In it, they&amp;rsquo;ll be breaking down what it takes to properly attract developers to an open-source project, sustaining development on an open-source project, and how to think about the &amp;ldquo;life-span&amp;rdquo; of an open-source project.
As always, laptops are encouraged and pizza will be provided.</description></item><item><title>DevOps</title><link>/events/2018-02-01-harris/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2018-02-01-harris/</guid><description>This week Harris Corporation will be going over DevOps - what it is, its impact and technologies, and how it will affect you and your career. Also, they will give us a brief overview of who they are and what they do. Harris has volunteered to sponsor various Open Source Club meetings for several years and we are very grateful to have them back again.
As always, laptops are encouraged and pizza will be provided.</description></item><item><title>Git Workshop and Elections</title><link>/events/2018-01-25-git-workshop/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2018-01-25-git-workshop/</guid><description>This week, we&amp;rsquo;ll be walking through one of the most common ways of contributing to an Open Source project, by using git and github. This will be a complete walkthrough of how to work collaboratively in the open source community.
Also, as promised, today elections will be held for the officer positions as listed on the website. As usual, the requirements for voting are as follows:
Member on the opensource club mailing list Attend at least one meeting during the semester Full time student for 2018-2019 school year As always, laptops are encouraged and pizza will be provided.</description></item><item><title>Ansible</title><link>/events/2018-01-18-ansible/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2018-01-18-ansible/</guid><description>This week, we&amp;rsquo;ll be talking about Ansible. Endorsed by RedHat, Ansible is used in industry for tasks such as configuration management or keeping servers synchronized with standardized settings. In the age of disposible systems (containers and virtual machines) configuration management tools such as Ansible are indispensible. What differentiates Ansible from other CM tools such as Puppet or Chef is that Ansible is agentless, and able to communicate to any device over regular old SSH!</description></item><item><title>Contribute to FOSS Projects</title><link>/events/2018-01-11-contribute-to-foss-projects/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2018-01-11-contribute-to-foss-projects/</guid><description>This week, we&amp;rsquo;ll be talking about how to get started contributing to FOSS projects. This should cover any skill level, so even if you&amp;rsquo;ve never made a &amp;ldquo;Hello World&amp;rdquo; you should come away having learned how to help out with your favorite projects. It will be this Thursday, 7:30 p.m. at CL 120.
As always, laptops are encouraged and pizza will be provided.</description></item><item><title>Developing OpenStack</title><link>/events/2017-11-30-openstack/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2017-11-30-openstack/</guid><description>This presentation will talk about a few of the challenges that David saw while working in the OpenStack community. For each challenge he wants to talk about how the issues were mitigated. There will be a heavy focus on the development process.
This is our last meeting of the semester, and we will discuss several changes that we are going to undertake over Winter Break and going into next semester.</description></item><item><title>Virtualization</title><link>/events/2017-11-02-virtualization/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2017-11-02-virtualization/</guid><description>The week one of our own will be giving a talk on virtualization! This will be a good chance to get some knowledge if you are interested, or to find out if you are interested. As always, free pizza will be provided!</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin and Blockchain Technology</title><link>/events/2017-10-26-bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2017-10-26-bitcoin/</guid><description>The cryptocurrency that recently broke $6000. Bitcoin is a sophisticated system in that it&amp;rsquo;s complex in its simplicity, and today I&amp;rsquo;ll try to explain how blockchain technology works and how it is the logical next step in the computing world.
This talk is taken straight from Brian Warner when he gave his talk Bitcoin: A Technical Introduction. You can follow along with the slides that are posted on his personal site: lothar.</description></item><item><title>Configfest</title><link>/events/2017-08-31-configfest/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2017-08-31-configfest/</guid><description>Browser Addons Ublock Origin Https Everywhere Decentraleyes Cookie Autodelete Taborama Tile Tabs xStyle Custom Settings Multi-threading https://medium.com/mozilla-tech/the-search-for-the-goldilocks-browser-and-why-firefox-may-be-just-right-for-you-1f520506aa35
Heavy Writing because of Saving Tabs https://www.servethehome.com/firefox-is-eating-your-ssd-here-is-how-to-fix-it/
Cache http://windows7themes.net/en-us/firefox-memory-cache-ssd/ http://forum.notebookreview.com/threads/ssd-owners-set-firefox-to-memory-cache-instead-of-disk.533359/
Tweak Tools Gnome-tweak-tool
Ubuntu Settings
Email Thunderbird OSU Buckeyemail Always use your full &amp;lt;name&amp;gt;.#@buckeyemail.osu.edu address
Protocol: IMAP Server: outlook.office365.com Port: 143 Connection Security: STARTTLS Authentication Method: Normal Password Protocol: SMTP Server: smtp.office365.com Port: 587 Connection Security: STARTTLS Authentication Method: Normal Password Mutt Riot Yet another Messaging Platform</description></item><item><title>What is Open Source</title><link>/events/2017-08-24-first-talk/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2017-08-24-first-talk/</guid><description>The Open Source Club at The Ohio State University Resources Servers Code Review Hardware Events Mailing List Constitution Volunteering Hours PyOhio Communication Be Excellent to Each Other Email Chat IRC Riot Kanboard Officers Benevolent Dictator - Ted Li (li.6998@osu.edu) Vice President - Andrew smacz Cziryak (cziryak.1@osu.edu) Treasurer - Jack Moore (moore.3337@osu.edu) System Administrator - John EDT Markiewicz (markiewicz.22@osu.edu) Advisor - Matt Black (black.</description></item><item><title>PyOhio</title><link>/events/2017-07-29-pyohio/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2017-07-29-pyohio/</guid><description>PyOhio July 29 &amp;amp; 30, 2017, at The Ohio Union pyohio.org What&amp;rsquo;s Python? An open source computer programming language loved by entry-level and expert programmers alike. It has broad applications across many disciplines, and is widely used by engineers, scientists, statisticians, analysts, mathematicians, AI developers, and others to build custom software.
Why Python? Among the top five programming languages on popularity and usage indices Popular websites like Reddit, Pinterest, Instagram, Youtube, and DropBox are built with Python Even companies like Facebook and Google use Python to manage their server&amp;rsquo;s software infrastructure A rich collection of free libraries make Python a cost-effective alternative to many existing proprietary commercial software packages Provides easy integration with and additional complementary packages for software tools commonly used in statistics and data science e.</description></item><item><title>VR Demo And An Adieu To Graduating Seniors</title><link>/events/2017-04-20-vr-demo-and-an-adieu-to-graduating-seniors/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2017-04-20-vr-demo-and-an-adieu-to-graduating-seniors/</guid><description>Join us Thursday April 20th at 19:00 in Dreese Labs 264, for a virtual reality workshop. We&amp;rsquo;ll use the Aframe framework made by Mozilla VR to work through a few simple VR examples. Before we get started with our adventure into VR, we&amp;rsquo;ll have a sendoff for our graduating seniors.
As always, there will be pizza and laptops are encouraged.
&amp;ndash; malide</description></item><item><title>Open Source Radio</title><link>/events/2017-04-13-open-source-radio/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2017-04-13-open-source-radio/</guid><description>This Thursday, April 13, at 19:00 in Dreese Labs 264, join the Open Source Club and Dan Zeleznikar, Ohio State ECE alumni and current LGS Signal Processing Engineer, for an overview of open source HW/SW that can be used for radio communications transceivers, including a demo of reverse engineering the controls of an RC car. Attendees are encouraged to bring their own RC toys for experimentation as well. Feel free to bring resumes, and dinner will be provided!</description></item><item><title>Email systems and management</title><link>/events/2017-04-06-email-systems-and-management/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2017-04-06-email-systems-and-management/</guid><description>Join us this Thursday, April 06, at 19:00 in Dreese 264 for a talk on email. Email is one of the oldest and widely used protocols on the internet today. This talk will discuss how we have tried to keep it safe from scammers and spammers while maintaining backwards compatibility. Additionally we will discuss how modern email systems are setup and how to set up email for your own domain.</description></item><item><title>Crypto War II</title><link>/events/2017-03-30-crypto-war-ii/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2017-03-30-crypto-war-ii/</guid><description>Join us Thursday March 30th, at 19:00 in Dreese Labs 264 for a talk with Matt Curtin, former OSC advisor and founder of Interhack, a computer expert firm with a history of cybersecurity expertise in and out of the courtroom. Matt Curtin will discuss the effect of government policy on infrastructure.
Government policy to address the real threat to our critical infrastructure is almost exactly wrong. Both Democratic and Republican administrations have absurdly taken the position that rather than hardening targets, vulnerabilities should be left open and weaponized.</description></item><item><title>An Intro to Rust</title><link>/events/2017-03-23-an-intro-to-rust-with-paradigm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2017-03-23-an-intro-to-rust-with-paradigm/</guid><description>Join us this Thursday, March 23rd in Dreese 264 at 19:00 for a talk by Daniel Thau, creator of Bedrock Linux.
Daniel &amp;ldquo;paradigm&amp;rdquo; Thau will introduce the Rust programming language. Rust is a programming language with a focus on both performance and correctness with an emphasis on compile-time assurances against memory and data race issues. The presentation will give an overview of the more notable aspects of Rust with the intent to equip the audience to readily learn more, if interested.</description></item><item><title>Ansible And Elections</title><link>/events/2017-03-09-ansible-and-elections/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2017-03-09-ansible-and-elections/</guid><description>Join us this Thursday, March 9th 2017, at 19:00 in Dreese 264 for a talk by Smacz on the popular automation software, Ansible. Used in industry for tasks such as configuration management, Ansible is often used to keep servers synchronized with standardized settings. Ansible was developed by RedHat to simplify automation and provide an easy to read syntax.
Elections for 2017-2018 officers are also Thursday. If you&amp;rsquo;re an undergraduate student graduating May of 2018 or later, you are a viable candidate.</description></item><item><title>Spring 2017 Open Source Club Officer Elections</title><link>/events/2017-03-06-sp17-elections/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2017-03-06-sp17-elections/</guid><description>Want to get more involved with OpenSource Club? Consider running for an officer position March 9th. Positions up for reelection are:
President Vice President Treasurer SysAdmin more as needed If you&amp;rsquo;d like more information on what these positions feel free to email president@opensource.osu.edu to ask the outgoing president about how the club runs.</description></item><item><title>Hack Night</title><link>/events/2017-03-02-hack-night/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2017-03-02-hack-night/</guid><description>Join us tonight at 19:00 for a hack night. Bring your projects and questions with you. Have a project that you&amp;rsquo;re working on that you could use help with, bring it with you. Have questions about an open source topic, bring it with you. This meeting is meant to be an opportunity to work on what you want with other enthusiasts as a resource.</description></item><item><title>Neural Networks and Deep Learning</title><link>/events/2017-02-23-neural-networks-and-deep-learning-with-capital-one/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2017-02-23-neural-networks-and-deep-learning-with-capital-one/</guid><description>Deep learning has become one of the hottest topics in computing in the past few years. Neural networks are not a new topic, but with the recent advances in computation capacity provided by hardware accelerators, in particular GPUs, they have gained new popularity. In this talk we present some of the concepts behind neural networks and deep learning, and then shift to the performance aspects of available solutions. We will finally focus on Tensorflow, an open source deep learning package, and provide a hands-on demo using it.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Talks</title><link>/events/2017-02-16-lightning-talks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2017-02-16-lightning-talks/</guid><description>Join us Thursday February 16 at 19:00 with your short talks on technology to present to the club. Talks should be between 5 and 10 minutes on a topic that you find fascinating. Previous lightning talks have included version control, OpenSCAD, Linux MultiMedia Studio, and gaming on Linux. Be creative and be supprotive to those presenting.</description></item><item><title>Idomatic Python</title><link>/events/2017-02-09-idiomatic-python/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2017-02-09-idiomatic-python/</guid><description>Join us Thursday February 9th, 2017 at 19:00 as Brian Costlow, a PyOhio board member and previous conference chair, presents on Python. A summary from Brian Costlow:
All languages, even programming languages, develop idioms. Python is such a flexible language that newcomers to the language sometimes end up writing &amp;ldquo;C in Python&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Java in Python&amp;rdquo;. This talk will cover some common pitfalls where there is more than one way to do it, and show you which one a seasoned Pythonista would reach for.</description></item><item><title>Résumé Workshop</title><link>/events/2017-02-02-rsum-workshop/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2017-02-02-rsum-workshop/</guid><description>Join us this Thursday, February 2nd 2017, at 19:00 as Former OSU grads from Harris Corporation discuss their jobs as software engineers at Harris Corporation. Learn how to properly format your resume to highlight your software skills, and include notable projects you’ve done as a student, to better catch the attention of software recruiters at high-tech companies.</description></item><item><title>MVAPICH and High Power Computing</title><link>/events/2017-01-26-mvapich-and-high-power-computing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2017-01-26-mvapich-and-high-power-computing/</guid><description>Join us Thursday January 26th at 19:00 in Caldwell 120 as Professor DK Panda, a distinguished scholar of the CSE department and member of the Network-Based Computing Laboratory at OSU.
The Network-Based Computing Laboratory at OSU/CSE in actively engaged in designing software libraries for supercomputers. The open-source MVAPICH software project at OSU/CSE has been enabling MPI libraries for TOP supercomputers in the World (including the latest #1st ranked) during the last decade.</description></item><item><title>Linux tips and tricks</title><link>/events/2017-01-19-linux-tips-and-tricks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2017-01-19-linux-tips-and-tricks/</guid><description>Join us Thursday January 19th, 2017 at 19:00 in Caldwell 120 as Stephen Haffner presents on some Linux tips and tricks.
This talk by Stephen Haffner wants to help make you a better Linux user! It will start with some quick tips on using the command line more efficiently, provide an overview of the organization of a Linux system, and finish up with a smattering of useful file, networking, and security tools available on most distributions.</description></item><item><title>Welcome Back</title><link>/events/2017-01-12-welcome-back/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2017-01-12-welcome-back/</guid><description>Join us on January 12th, 2017 at 19:00 in Caldwell 120 as we discuss the upcoming semester and how to contribute to open source.</description></item><item><title>Von Neumann machines</title><link>/events/2016-12-01-von-neumann-machines/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2016-12-01-von-neumann-machines/</guid><description>Join us this Thursday as Jon Arnett presents on Von Neumann machines and to say goodbye to our graduating seniors. The following is a brief excerpt on Von Neumann machines from Jon Arnett:
&amp;ldquo;Imagine a probe gliding through the galaxy. It lands on a planet, and begins to mine. After a while, it uses the materials it has collected to construct a replica of itself. The replica launches into space. The original probe sets off to explore its new found world, sending data back to Earth.</description></item><item><title>Wikipedia in your next project</title><link>/events/2016-11-17-wikipedia-in-your-next-project/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2016-11-17-wikipedia-in-your-next-project/</guid><description>Kevin Payravi from Wikipedia Connection will present on how to incorporate Wikipedia and its sister projects into your next project. The presentation will explore MediaWiki (the software behind Wikipedia), the MediaWiki API, machine learning and botting with Wikipedia, Wikidata (a free structured knowledgebase), and more. There will be an introduction to Tool Labs, Wikimedia&amp;rsquo;s free hosting environment for Wikimedia projects, as well as a look at some of the cool open source projects that have been developed for Wikipedia - which include vandalism-detecting bots, edit gamification, and making live music out of Wikipedia edits.</description></item><item><title>The ELK Stack</title><link>/events/2016-11-10-the-elk-stack/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2016-11-10-the-elk-stack/</guid><description>This Thursday, November 10th 2016, David Soller will be presenting the ELK stack.
The talk will center around the ELK stack and its ability “to take data from any source and search, analyze, and visualize it in real time.”(Elastic.co) Each of the ELK stacks open source projects Elasticsearch, Logstash and Kibana will be covered.</description></item><item><title>DDWRT and OpenWRT, free your router</title><link>/events/2016-11-03-ddwrt-and-openwrt-free-your-router/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2016-11-03-ddwrt-and-openwrt-free-your-router/</guid><description>Join us Thursday November 3rd, 2016 at 19:00 in Caldwell 120 to learn about DD-WRT and OpenWRT, two Linux distributions for your wireless router. You&amp;rsquo;ll learn how to turn your cheap consumer router into fully-featured professional hardware with the power of open source.</description></item><item><title>Wireless Security</title><link>/events/2016-10-27-wireless-security/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2016-10-27-wireless-security/</guid><description>Most of us use wireless networks every day. But do we really understand the security implications of flinging packets over the air?
Join us this Thursday, October 26 2016 as William Osler gives a talk covering the basics of wireless network security, including a demonstration of a fun attack on legacy wireless encryption standards.</description></item><item><title>PGP Key Signing Party</title><link>/events/2016-10-20-pgp-keysigning-party/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2016-10-20-pgp-keysigning-party/</guid><description>Pretty Good Privacy(PGP) is a great way to communicate privately, but also to verify the identity of an online source. PGP is commonly used in fields such as journalism when identity is a must or when signing your code. PGP can also be used to encrypt communications so that only one party can read it.
Join us this Thursday, October 20, 2016, as Michael Yanovich describes the functionality of PGP and demonstrates how to use it.</description></item><item><title>Ohio LinuxFest</title><link>/events/2016-10-09-ohio-linuxfest/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2016-10-09-ohio-linuxfest/</guid><description>Come join us today and tomorrow to enjoy Ohio LinuxFest. It&amp;rsquo;s a great opportunity to both learn about Open Source Software and meet other members of the Open Source community. Open Source club will be there at the Open Source Club booth around 1600EDT and we&amp;rsquo;d love to see you guys stop by to say hello!</description></item><item><title>Android vulnerabilities and security</title><link>/events/2016-10-06-android-vulnerabilities-and-security/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2016-10-06-android-vulnerabilities-and-security/</guid><description>Come join us Thursday October 6th at 19:00EDT, as Chandler Freeman talks about Android vulnerabilities and the world of mobile security. Chandler will do a brief analysis given some newer exploits, and try to determine how widespread the vulnerabilities still are in the ecosystem.
Did you know about Ohio Linux Fest? It&amp;rsquo;s a great opportunity to learn from some great speakers and meet fellow FLOSS enthusiasts. You can register for FREE at https://ohiolinux.</description></item><item><title>Vim vs Emacs</title><link>/events/2016-09-24-vim-vs-emacs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2016-09-24-vim-vs-emacs/</guid><description>Join us Thursday, September 29th, at 19:00 EDT, as we talk about the storied editors that have been pitted against each other for forty years. The speed and extensible nature of these editors have made them very popular along with the ability to be ran headless unlike modern day editors. Learning one of these two editors is strongly advised in order to be effective in any environment.</description></item><item><title>Harris Corp on embedded software</title><link>/events/2016-09-22-harris-corp-on-embedded-software/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2016-09-22-harris-corp-on-embedded-software/</guid><description>Join us this Thursday, September 22, at 19:00EDT as Tim Armstrong from Harris Corporation talks about embedded software. Tim is an Ohio State alumni and would love to answer your questions about anything from embedded software to life after college.</description></item><item><title>Capital One presents trends in computing</title><link>/events/2016-09-15-capital-one-presents-trends-in-computing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2016-09-15-capital-one-presents-trends-in-computing/</guid><description>Join us this Thursday as Kapil Thangavelu, the Data Engineering Director from Capital One, gives us an industry view of trends in computing. Topics will include big data, the cloud, and containers. Kapil will also talk about opensource projects from Capital One and why opensource is important in industry.</description></item><item><title>Intro to the Command line</title><link>/events/2016-09-08-intro-to-the-commandline/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2016-09-08-intro-to-the-commandline/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re new to the command line, stop on by and we can get you comfortable with the terminal. Be it moving around, updating software, or anything else in your daily computing needs.
If you can navigate your way around the terminal just fine, don&amp;rsquo;t skip this meeting yet, we&amp;rsquo;ll be discussing different shells and tips and tricks. Want to get a nice customized setup nice and quick, try FISH or OH-MY-ZSH.</description></item><item><title>InstallFest</title><link>/events/2016-09-01-installfest/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2016-09-01-installfest/</guid><description>Interested in running Linux or BSD, but haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten around to installing it? Wanted to change distros, but you didn&amp;rsquo;t have the time? Come to our installfest and take the time to eat some pizza and install the OS of your dreams. We&amp;rsquo;ll have 5 copies of Ubuntu, 3 copies of Mint, 2 copies of Elementary, one OpenBSD stick, and one Arch ISO. If nothing strikes your fancy, we can download it!</description></item><item><title>Welcome To Open Source</title><link>/events/2016-08-25-welcome-to-open-source/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2016-08-25-welcome-to-open-source/</guid><description>Come join us August 25th at 19:00 in Caldwell 120 to learn what Open Source is and why you should use it. You&amp;rsquo;ll meet our officers for the year, and there will be plenty of time for socializing and eating pizza!</description></item><item><title>Why Open Source at Microsoft?</title><link>/events/2016-04-21-why-open-source-at-microsoft/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2016-04-21-why-open-source-at-microsoft/</guid><description>Thursday, 2016/04/21 at 7:00PM in Caldwell Labs 120
What started as a war is turning to a love affair. Over the last two decades, Microsoft has moved from a fierce opponent of the penguin to recently being welcomed by Ubuntu, Red Hat and others. Come for an interactive discussion of Microsoft’s journey with Open Source and see some demos of the new Bash on Windows and .Net Core.
Brian Sherwin is a Sr.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to FreeBSD</title><link>/events/2016-04-14-freebsd/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2016-04-14-freebsd/</guid><description>Thursday, 2016/04/14 at 7:00PM in Caldwell Labs 120
This talk is aimed at giving a overview of the operating system, why to use it, and some of its wonderful features such as the z file system (zfs), jails, and ports/pkg (its software build system). Unlike what many might think the BSD projects are not dead. They are heavily used, maintained, developed, and documented by many people from around the world ranging from hobbyists to multimillion dollar companies.</description></item><item><title>Package managers and Open Source election</title><link>/events/2016-04-07-package_managers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2016-04-07-package_managers/</guid><description>Thursday, 2016/04/07 at 7:00PM in Caldwell Labs 120
This Thursday, Brandon Moore will present on package managers. From distro-based package managers to project-based package managers, we will discuss what a package manager is, the advantages and disadvantages of package managers, the recent issue with the mass-unpublishing of Node modules, and more.
Don&amp;rsquo;t forget that the election will also occur at this meeting. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t registered to vote yet then please get in contact with the officers.</description></item><item><title>Bedrock Linux</title><link>/events/2016-03-31-bedrock_linux/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2016-03-31-bedrock_linux/</guid><description>Thursday, 2016/03/31 at 7:00PM in Caldwell Labs 120
Daniel &amp;ldquo;paradigm&amp;rdquo; Thau will present Bedrock Linux, a Linux distribution which allows the use of software from a variety of typically mutually exclusive Linux distributions, simultaneously and transparently.
If one would like a rock-solid stable base (for example, from Debian or a RHEL clone) yet still have easy access to cutting-edge packages (from, say, Arch Linux), automate compiling packages with Gentoo&amp;rsquo;s portage, and ensure that software aimed only for the ever popular Ubuntu will run smoothly - all at the same time, in the same distribution - Bedrock Linux will provide a means to achieve this.</description></item><item><title>Spring LAN Party</title><link>/events/2016-03-26-lan-party/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2016-03-26-lan-party/</guid><description>BuckeyeLAN and Open Source Club team up to bring you the first Open Source LAN party of 2016! Come join us in the Senate Chamber Room at the Ohio Union on Saturday 26 March 2016 from 2 PM to 8 PM. We plan on playing a variety of open source &amp;amp; Linux games including OpenRCT2, Team Fortress 2, TeeWorlds, and much more!</description></item><item><title>A Recap of NICAR, and open source in journalism</title><link>/events/2016-03-24-nicar_recap/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2016-03-24-nicar_recap/</guid><description>Open Source Club and Lantern alumnus Ben keith will talk about open source software in journalism. Topics covered will include notable newsroom teams working in the open, tools available for anyone to use, conferences and training available, and some story ideas from the conference.
This talk will also be a recap of NICAR 2016, and give overviews of some talks given there.
This talk is suitable for all audiences, and journalism students are particularly encouraged to come.</description></item><item><title>Open Source and Linux Gaming</title><link>/events/2016-03-10-linux_gaming/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2016-03-10-linux_gaming/</guid><description>Level up this Thursday, 2016/03/10 at 7:00pm in Caldwell Labs 120 as Nikit Malkan and William Osler present a talk on gaming with Linux. From free software games like 0 A.D. and Super Tux Cart to proprietary games that run with a compatibility layer, come learn about some of the essentials for getting the most game out of your Linux system. We&amp;rsquo;ll also be covering details like how to get set up and going in Wine, games you can run Linux servers for, game engines with Linux support and more.</description></item><item><title>Open Source Hardware and Hobby Electronics</title><link>/events/2016-03-03-hobby_electronics/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2016-03-03-hobby_electronics/</guid><description>Thursday, 2016/03/03 at 7:00pm in Caldwell Labs 120
Alex Fuhr will be giving an intro to open-source hardware and hobby electronics. This talk is designed for those who are entering the Makeathon or who just want to learn more about hardware in general, and will cover topics such as microcontrollers, digit and analog I/O, prototyping tools, serial communication protocols, and potential project ideas.
It&amp;rsquo;s not too late to sign up for the Makeathon this Saturday (March 5th).</description></item><item><title>Forensic Data Analysis</title><link>/events/2016-02-25-forensic_computer_analysis/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2016-02-25-forensic_computer_analysis/</guid><description>Thursday, 2016/02/25 at 7:00pm in Caldwell Labs 120
This week Matt Curtin will present on forensic data analysis. This will focus on the use of technology in legal cases. Matt Curtin, and his company Interhack Corporation, has addressed courts on the topics of wiretapping, data breaches, and more. Matt Curtin will address the merits of opensource software in forensic data analysis in court rooms in order to reach a resolution that may be much more controversial when using proprietary software.</description></item><item><title>Intermediate Vim</title><link>/events/2016-02-18-vim_intermediate/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2016-02-18-vim_intermediate/</guid><description>Thursday, 2016/02/18 at 7:00pm in Caldwell Labs 120
This talk is targeted at the Vim user who is looking to take their knowledge of the editor to the next level. It can take several years to master a text editor in all it&amp;rsquo;s intricacies, and Vim is no exception. Having used Vim for the last four years or so, I will try to impart some of the lessons I have learned - not just about how to use Vim, but also about how to learn to use Vim.</description></item><item><title>Pure Data</title><link>/events/2016-02-04-pure_data/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2016-02-04-pure_data/</guid><description>Thursday, 2016/02/04 at 7:00pm in Caldwell Labs 120, Alex Fuhr will present Pure Data. Pure Data is an open source visual programming language for audio, graphic, and signal processing. This talk will start with the basic concepts of the language, and then dive deeper into topics such as audio generation and manipulation, helpful subroutines, graphical processing, connecting to an Arduino, and more advanced audio examples.
In order to follow along with all the demos, make sure to install pd-extended (Pure Data with extra libraries) before the meeting.</description></item><item><title>Arch Linux</title><link>/events/2016-01-28-arch_linux/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2016-01-28-arch_linux/</guid><description>Thursday&amp;rsquo;s talk will be on installing Arch Linux, performed by our longtime sysadmin William Osler. I also want to finalize a schedule for at least the next couple weeks after gauging interest at last week&amp;rsquo;s meeting.
Many distributions like Ubuntu or Fedora are configured and set up with out-of-the box programs and features. While this is very convenient, digging deeper and setting up a system yourself will allow you to understand your system and better customize it to your needs.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Planning + Lightning Talks</title><link>/events/2016-01-21-lightning_talks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2016-01-21-lightning_talks/</guid><description>Tonight&amp;rsquo;s meeting will be drafting future talks for the semester + some lightning talks; and I&amp;rsquo;m going to give a condensed version of a powerpoint at a conference that I saw on Monday dealing with the economics of zero-day vulnerabilities. Future meeting dates will posted on the website as they&amp;rsquo;re determined.</description></item><item><title>Welcome Back</title><link>/events/2016-01-14-welcome-back/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2016-01-14-welcome-back/</guid><description>This Thursday, January 14th at 7PM in Caldwell 120, we will be voting on whether or not to amend our club&amp;rsquo;s constitution. So for that reason, I encourage everyones' attendance.</description></item><item><title>Meteor.js</title><link>/events/2015-12-10-meteor/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2015-12-10-meteor/</guid><description>This Thursday, December 10th at 7PM in Caldwell 120, I will be discussing / demoing Meteor.js.
&amp;ldquo;Meteor is a full-stack JavaScript App Platform that assemble all the pieces you need to build modern web and mobile apps, with a single JavaScript codebase.&amp;rdquo;
Laptops are encouraged but not required, and as always, there will be pizza.
Good luck on exams.</description></item><item><title>Redis</title><link>/events/2015-12-03-redis/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2015-12-03-redis/</guid><description>This Thursday, December 3rd at 7PM in Caldwell 120, J3RN will be talking about Redis, the in-memory key-value store.
Redis is a nice (and fast!) alternative to using a database if the values you are trying to store are simple, and is commonly used for caching. The types that Redis natively supports are strings, hashes, lists, sets, and sorted sets. Additionally, Redis has other cool features such as a configurable level of on-disk persistence and &amp;ldquo;sentinels&amp;rdquo; for high availability.</description></item><item><title>Network Maintenance and Upgrades</title><link>/events/2015-11-26-no-meeting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2015-11-26-no-meeting/</guid><description>The club systems will be undergoing scheduled maintenance this weekend, so expect downtime. Our sysadmin, William, will be reverting Gluster. Also, We will be upgrading Stallman&amp;rsquo;s ram from 4GB ram to 12GB, in addition to replacing the power supply.</description></item><item><title>Password Management</title><link>/events/2015-11-19-password-management/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2015-11-19-password-management/</guid><description>This Thursday, November 19th at 7PM in Caldwell 120, We will discuss the many ways to safe guard/manage your passwords. Everyone at sometime or another has relied on their browser to store sensitive credentials quite often due to sheer simplicity. Did you know up until 2013 Chromium was storing a user&amp;rsquo;s credentials in PlainText.
Now if your the type that likes to use a password manager, you might already be aware that not all services are created equal.</description></item><item><title>Git - An Introduction and Explanation</title><link>/events/2015-11-12-git-introduction-and-explanation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2015-11-12-git-introduction-and-explanation/</guid><description>Come join us Thursday, the 12th of November, as Nikit &amp;ldquo;Nefari0uss&amp;rdquo; Malkan talks about Git source control and how to use it for your projects (and perhaps even an upcoming hackathon).
I will talk about the different models of work flow, how source control plays a role, and then will talk extensively about how Git works. Following that, I will briefly cover how to use some basic Git commands and how to set it up quickly for the upcoming OHI/O 2015 hackathon.</description></item><item><title>License to Code</title><link>/events/2015-11-05-license-to-code/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2015-11-05-license-to-code/</guid><description>Come join us Thursday, the fifth of November, as Brandon Moore talks about licenses and why you should use one on any project you work on. Licensing is a key part of the open source community, and your choices are diverse. We will talk about licenses ranging from the copyleft to the copyright, the unlicense to the Apache license. We will discuss how you choose your license for a project and what implications your choice has, and more importantly what a lack of choosing a license means and how it affects the Open Source community.</description></item><item><title>Wireless Security and Penetration Testing</title><link>/events/2015-10-29-wireless-security-and-penetration-testing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2015-10-29-wireless-security-and-penetration-testing/</guid><description>This Thursday, October 29th at 7PM in Caldwell 120, I, Eli Gladman, will speak on wireless security and penetration testing. Specifically I will be going over common network vulnerabilities and misconceptions. After a brief introduction, I will demonstrate how to brute force particular types of WiFi access points due to their inherently insecure &amp;ldquo;encryption&amp;rdquo;. I encourage people to follow along and learn the most they can about wireless security.
The intention of this talk is to educate members with respect to securing their own local networks.</description></item><item><title>Working in a Production Environment</title><link>/events/2015-10-22-covermymeds/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2015-10-22-covermymeds/</guid><description>Hi everyone,
This Thursday at 7:00PM in Caldwell Labs 120, Jay Bobo and Vasanth Pappu from CoverMyMeds will discuss what it&amp;rsquo;s like working in a production environment. For those that are unfamiliar, CoverMyMeds is a Columbus startup that automates the Prior Authorization process in the healthcare industry. I urge everyone to go check them out!
Laptops are encouraged but not required, and as always, there will be pizza.</description></item><item><title>Startup Weekend</title><link>/events/2015-10-20-startup-weekend/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2015-10-20-startup-weekend/</guid><description>Startup Weekend is November 20th. Learn More.
Tickets are $100 however if you email us we can provide you with a discount code to reduce the ticket price to $35.</description></item><item><title>BDAA Career Fair</title><link>/events/2015-10-12-bdaa-career-fair/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2015-10-12-bdaa-career-fair/</guid><description>Come volunteer at the BBDA Career Fair.
Date: Wednesday, October 21st, 2015 Where: The Union Cartoon Room Time: 12-3pm Various volunteers needed from 9:30 am-3:30pm</description></item><item><title>Exploring Majors Fair</title><link>/events/2015-10-12-exploring-majors-fair/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2015-10-12-exploring-majors-fair/</guid><description>Come volunteer at the Exploring Majors Fair.
Date: Monday, October 12th, 2015 Where: Physics Research Building Time: 11am-2pm Volunteers needed:
Shift 1: 11am-12:30 Shift 2: 12:30-3pm They are seeking volunteers in the following majors/pre-majors:
Chemical Engineering Mechanical Engineering Aerospace They need two volunteers from each department for each shift (a total of 12 volunteer slots)</description></item><item><title>Engineering Homecoming Tailgate</title><link>/events/2015-10-10-homecoming-tailgate/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2015-10-10-homecoming-tailgate/</guid><description>Come volunteer at the Engineering Homecoming Tailgate.
Date: Saturday, October 10th, 2015 Where: Knowlton Hall Plaza Time: 9-11am Various shifts needed from 7 am-12pm
Positions:
event setup/cleanup greeters food &amp;amp; beverage line attendants registration staff trivia competition assistants</description></item><item><title>Pretty Good Privacy &amp; Secure communications with PGP</title><link>/events/2015-10-08-gpg/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2015-10-08-gpg/</guid><description>This Thursday, October 8, at 7PM in Caldwell 120, William Osler will be presenting on GPG, the GNU implantation of the PGP standard. PGP is a tool that allows people to communicate with each other securely, even if they&amp;rsquo;ve never met in person. We&amp;rsquo;ll talk about the Web of Trust concept, and how you can help expand it via key signing.
After the meeting, we&amp;rsquo;ll have a &amp;ldquo;key signing party&amp;rdquo;. If you&amp;rsquo;ve never heard of this: don&amp;rsquo;t worry, we&amp;rsquo;ll talk about it during the presentation.</description></item><item><title>Ohio LinuxFest 2015</title><link>/events/2015-10-03-ohio-linux-fest/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2015-10-03-ohio-linux-fest/</guid><description>The Open Source Club is a proud sponsor of Ohio LinuxFest 2015. So come out and join us on October 2nd &amp;amp; 3rd at the Greater Columbus Convention Center.</description></item><item><title>Logical Volumes and Fancy Filesystems</title><link>/events/2015-10-01-filesystems/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2015-10-01-filesystems/</guid><description>This Thursday, October 1, at 7PM in Caldwell 120, Matt Meinwald will speak on logical volume management, specifically covering LVM, ZFS, and Btrfs. He will discuss a bit of the background and history of these systems, and describe the key features each provides. Hopefully by the end of this talk you will consider throwing away your legacy partitions (after taking backups!) and embracing these technologies.
This weekend (October 2nd &amp;amp; 3rd) is the thirteenth annual Ohio LinuxFest held in the greater Columbus Convention Center.</description></item><item><title>Open Source at Facebook</title><link>/events/2015-09-24-opensource-at-facebook/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2015-09-24-opensource-at-facebook/</guid><description>This Thursday, 2015/09/24 at 7:00PM in Caldwell Labs 120, Patrick Shuff will present &amp;ldquo;Open Source at Facebook&amp;rdquo;. Description follows:
Facebook serves requests for over 1.3 billion people every month. I will give a brief overview of our Traffic/CDN (e.g. images and videos) infrastructure and how open source software is core to being able to deliver all of those bits to the world every day!
Patrick Shuff is a production engineer on the traffic team at Facebook.</description></item><item><title>Engineering Expo Career Fair</title><link>/events/2015-09-23-ecouncil-volunteering/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2015-09-23-ecouncil-volunteering/</guid><description>Please consider volunteering for the Engineering Expo Career Fair on September 22nd &amp;amp; 23rd on behalf of the Open Source Club. If you are interested sign up here</description></item><item><title>Lightning Talks</title><link>/events/2015-09-17-lightning-talks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2015-09-17-lightning-talks/</guid><description>Hi everyone,
This Thursday, 2015/09/17 at 7:00PM in Caldwell Labs 120, we will be holding lightning talks. For the uninitiated, lightning talks are brief presentations given by YOU. Talks are given in succession and can vary in subject matter. To get the ball rolling, I will demo Docker, a way to package your applications. I encourage everyone to present something that they&amp;rsquo;re passionate about.</description></item><item><title>OHI/O 2015 Hackathon</title><link>/events/2015-09-15-ohio-hackathon/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2015-09-15-ohio-hackathon/</guid><description>The 2015 OHI/O Hackathon is fast approaching. Register now.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to the Command Line</title><link>/events/2015-09-10-command-line/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2015-09-10-command-line/</guid><description>Hi everyone,
This Thursday, September 10 in Caldwell Labs 120, Bobby Reynolds and I will present an Introduction to the Command Line. This talk, given its nature is geared towards beginners. The talk will cover the following:
how to efficiently navigate directory trees basic regex how to remove the &amp;ldquo;french language pack&amp;rdquo; cough cough rm -fr / file creation, deletion, relocation, etc bash aliases script execution daemons how to compile packages from source useful one line commands</description></item><item><title>Linux Installfest</title><link>/events/2015-08-30-linux-installfest/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2015-08-30-linux-installfest/</guid><description>Hi everyone,
This Thursday, 2015/08/30 at 7:00PM in Caldwell Labs 120, the Open Source Club will hold our annual Linux Installfest. We&amp;rsquo;ll be helping you to install GNU/Linux on your machines, and will be available to answer any questions you may have. We will be providing a handful of bootable USBs and discs, preloaded with various linux distributions.
Laptops and chargers are encouraged but not required, and as always, there will be pizza.</description></item><item><title>First Meeting of the Semester</title><link>/events/2015-08-27-first-meeting-of-the-semester/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2015-08-27-first-meeting-of-the-semester/</guid><description>This Thursday, 2015/08/27 at 7:00PM in Caldwell Labs 120, Eli Gladman and the Open Source Club will present our very first meeting of the 2015-2016 academic year.
This meeting, geared toward beginners, gives an overview of the club including what we do and why we care. Additionally, this meeting is more social in nature with plenty of time to meet new people and network around.</description></item><item><title>Student Involvement Fair</title><link>/events/2015-08-23-sif/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2015-08-23-sif/</guid><description>Hi everyone,
This Sunday, 2015/08/23 is the annual Student Involvement fair on the Oval. We will be in the vicinity of Mendenhall and Hagerty Hall from 5:00PM to 8:00PM. We encourage people to stop by our table.</description></item><item><title>Advanced Vim Tutor</title><link>/events/2015-04-23-advanced-vim-tutor/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2015-04-23-advanced-vim-tutor/</guid><description>This Thursday, 2015/04/23 at 7:00PM in Caldwell Labs 120, Daniel Thau will present a tour of Vim functionality. Prior Vim experience is not required. This presentation will aim to cover things at a high-level in order to cover a broad number of Vim subsystems. This is done in the hopes of getting to new topics not covered in previous OSC Vim presentations. However, but if requested the presenter can go into further detail on any of the discussed items - do not hesitate to speak up and ask for further detail.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Talks</title><link>/events/2015-04-16-lightning-talks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2015-04-16-lightning-talks/</guid><description>Hi everyone,
This Thursday, 2015-04-16 @ 7:00pm in Caldwell Labs 120, The Open Source Club will present Lightning Talks.
This will be an informal space: Anyone who wants to speak will be granted a minimum of 5 minutes to share their topic of choice. Slides aren&amp;rsquo;t required at all- come share something you&amp;rsquo;re working on or something you love.
In the past, these are great opportunities to get better at speaking in order to do full meeting.</description></item><item><title>Cryptocurrencies and Elections</title><link>/events/2015-04-09-cryptocurrencies-and-elections/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2015-04-09-cryptocurrencies-and-elections/</guid><description>Thursday, 2015-04-09, Alex Krieger will present Cryptocurrencies. This will provide more of the technical details of how these schemes (such as Bitcoin, Litecoin, and Dogecoin) work.
In addition, there will be elections this week. As always, membership is required to vote. As defined by our constitution, this is having attended at least one meeting prior.
Laptops are encouraged but not required, and as always, there will be pizza.</description></item><item><title>BeagleBone and Embedded Linux</title><link>/events/2015-04-02-beaglebone-and-embedded-linux/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2015-04-02-beaglebone-and-embedded-linux/</guid><description>Thursday, 2015-04-02 at 7:00pm in Caldwell Labs 120, Eli Gladman will be speaking about BeagleBone. A short description follows:
My talk will include a brief overview of embedded Linux, particularly what sets it apart from traditional architectures. The majority of my talk will however focus on the BeagleBone Bone and its capabilities running embedded Linux. During my talk I will be demonstrating a series of example projects coded live.
In addition, we will take time at the beginning of the meeting to go over officer positions and their responsibilities, in anticipation for next week&amp;rsquo;s elections.</description></item><item><title>PostgreSQL</title><link>/events/2015-03-26-postgresql/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2015-03-26-postgresql/</guid><description>This Thursday, 2015-03-26 at 7:00pm in Caldwell Labs 120, Jeff Casavant will be speaking about PostgreSQL. A short description follows:
I&amp;rsquo;ll be talking about the free and open-source relational database system PostgreSQL. At gearDigital, the company I work for, we use it for our entire data infrastructure. It closely adheres to the SQL standard, and is highly extensible, which gives it some interesting (and unique) capabilities. I&amp;rsquo;ll detail some of the more interesting things you can do with Postgres during my talk - including using it as a search engine, as a GIS database, and as a social media client.</description></item><item><title>Linux Multimedia</title><link>/events/2015-03-12-linux-multimedia/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2015-03-12-linux-multimedia/</guid><description>This Thursday, 2015-03-12 at 7:00pm in Caldwell Labs 120, Brandon Dahl will present Linux Multimedia. A short description follows:
Brandon will be talking about the basics of using LMMS (Linux Multimedia Studio) to produce music. We&amp;rsquo;ll go over creating tracks, combining tracks, adding FX to the tracks, automation, and mixing tracks.
Laptops are encouraged but not required, and as always, there will be pizza.</description></item><item><title>System Updates</title><link>/events/2015-03-09-system-updates/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2015-03-09-system-updates/</guid><description>Update on the stallman2 migration:
It&amp;rsquo;s happening! The largest of the remaining tasks has been completed and we&amp;rsquo;re almost all set to go. Downtime will be scheduled this Friday starting at 3pm until I have no clue when as we do a final sync of the data, physically move the hardware, and verify that everything is operating correctly.
Since stallman2 is a fresh start, it may not have all the software that stallman currently has.</description></item><item><title>ownCloud</title><link>/events/2015-03-05-owncloud/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2015-03-05-owncloud/</guid><description>This Thursday, 2015-03-05 at 7:00pm in Caldwell Labs 120, Stephen Haffner will present Owncloud. This talk will go over pros and cons of Owncloud, as well as how it stacks up against other self-hosted file storage solutions. There will also be a demo of setting up and using ownCloud.
Laptops are encouraged but not required, and as always, there will be pizza.</description></item><item><title>Open Source and Web Browsers</title><link>/events/2015-02-26-open-source-and-web-browsers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2015-02-26-open-source-and-web-browsers/</guid><description>Thursday, 2015-02-26 at 7:00pm in Caldwell Labs 120, Nikit Malkan (Treasurer of the Open Source Club) will present Open Source and Web Browsers. A short description follows:
For this week&amp;rsquo;s meeting I will be going over Web browsers. I will talk about their many uses and perhaps some unknown features, give a brief history about the browser wars, and go over the major Web browsers of the past and present. Assuming sufficient time is left, I will end by going over my personalized Firefox setup and some of the many unique addons/features that make Firefox still worth using.</description></item><item><title>MediaWiki</title><link>/events/2015-02-12-mediawiki/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2015-02-12-mediawiki/</guid><description>This Thursday, 2015-02-12 at 7:00pm in Caldwell Labs 120, Kevin Payravi will present &amp;ldquo;MediaWiki&amp;rdquo;. Description follows:
&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll be introducing MediaWiki, Wikimedia&amp;rsquo;s open-source software for powering thousands of wikis (including Wikipedia). We&amp;rsquo;ll take a look at its development, how anyone can contribute, and do a quick set up on a DigitalOcean droplet. &amp;quot;
Laptops are encouraged but not required, and as always, there will be pizza.</description></item><item><title>Rosetta</title><link>/events/2015-02-05-rosetta/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2015-02-05-rosetta/</guid><description>Thursday, 2015-02-05 at 7:00pm in Caldwell Labs 120, representatives from Rosetta will be around to speak about the company and meet you. There will be nicer pizza than usual.
If anyone is interested in their on-campus interviews this Wednesday, please reply to this message and I&amp;rsquo;ll forward you on. Rosetta is looking for:
Full time: -Software Developer -Front-End Developer -Infrastructure Engineer
Internships: -Front-End Developer -Infrastructure Engineer
Laptops are encouraged but not required, and as always, there will be pizza.</description></item><item><title>Python</title><link>/events/2015-01-29-python/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2015-01-29-python/</guid><description>Thursday, 2015-01-29 at 7:00pm in Caldwell Labs 120, Chris Wallace and George Kvaratskhelia will preset &amp;ldquo;Python&amp;rdquo;.
This talk will cover the basics of the language, from basic syntax and datatypes to the interpreter. At the end, George will show off Django, an MVC web framework using python.
Laptops are encouraged but not required, and as always, there will be pizza.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Web Development</title><link>/events/2015-01-22-introduction-to-web-development/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2015-01-22-introduction-to-web-development/</guid><description>Thursday, 2015-01-22, Jon Arnett (President of the Collegiate Web Developer Group here on campus) and Eli Gladman will present &amp;ldquo;Intro to Web Development&amp;rdquo;. A description from Jon follows:
Eli and I will be giving an introduction to web development using Ruby on Rails. Ruby is an open source programming language that first surfaced in the 90&amp;rsquo;s, and gained popularity through it&amp;rsquo;s expressive syntax and powerful features, such as metaprogramming. The Rails web development framework is written in Ruby, and is known for allowing developers to iterate extremely quickly.</description></item><item><title>Welcome Back</title><link>/events/2015-01-15-welcome-back/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2015-01-15-welcome-back/</guid><description>This Thursday, 2015/01/15 at 7:00pm in Caldwell Labs 120, The Open Source Club will present &amp;ldquo;Welcome Back&amp;rdquo;. We&amp;rsquo;ll be around to socialize and plan the upcoming meetings.</description></item><item><title>Raspberry Pi</title><link>/events/2014-12-04-raspberry-pi/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2014-12-04-raspberry-pi/</guid><description>This Thursday, 2014/12/04 at 7:00pm in Caldwell Labs 120, The Open Source Club will present &amp;ldquo;Raspberry Pi&amp;rdquo;. Come by to learn all about the board and it&amp;rsquo;s alternatives, or just check out the cool projects club members have been working on. If you yourself have done something interesting with your pi, show it off!
This will be our last meeting of the Autumn 2014 semester. As per usual, we will do a goodbye to graduating seniors at the beginning of the meeting.</description></item><item><title>Web Privacy</title><link>/events/2014-11-13-web-privacy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2014-11-13-web-privacy/</guid><description>Thursday 2014/11/13, at 7:00pm in Caldwell Labs 120 we will be discussing Internet Privacy, as well as tools that can keep you anonymous on the Internet. Topics will include Tor, Firefox Extensions, and Darknets, as well as a discussion on technical privacy.
Laptops are encouraged but not required, and as always, there will be pizza.</description></item><item><title>Intellidu</title><link>/events/2014-11-06-intellidu/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2014-11-06-intellidu/</guid><description>This Thursday, 2014-11-06 in Caldwell Labs 120, John Simerlink will present his project &amp;ldquo;Intellidu&amp;rdquo;. His blurb follows:
Basically I&amp;rsquo;m building an education platform with a few friends that heavily uses data analytics and A/B testing to allow teacher to iteratively improve their courses. Teachers or uses will be able to empirically test out educational psychology research and apply them into any course imaginable.
&amp;ldquo;Intellidu&amp;rdquo;: Our app is designed to make you learn the quickest possible in any subject.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Security Concepts</title><link>/events/2014-11-02-introduction-to-security-concepts/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2014-11-02-introduction-to-security-concepts/</guid><description>Thursday, 2014-11-02 at 7:00pm in Caldwell Lab 120, John Toterhi of Battelle will present &amp;ldquo;Introduction to Security Concepts.&amp;rdquo;
The talk will be a high level overview of the software security industry and the methods used to find and exploit software vulnerabilities. Topics will include common vulnerabilities and exposures (CVE), common enumerations and weaknesses (CWE), software fuzzing, reverse engineering, binary diffing, and source code auditing. We&amp;rsquo;ll also talk about the role Capture the Flag (CTF) plays in developing the skills typically used in software security research and the new OSU CTF team.</description></item><item><title>Elixir</title><link>/events/2014-10-30-elixir/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2014-10-30-elixir/</guid><description>Thursday, 2014-10-30 at 7:00pm in Caldwell Labs 120, Jon Arnett will present Elixir. Description follows:
From the metaphorical ashes of the mostly-forgotten language Erlang, arises a promising successor, Elixir. With an intuitive syntax inherited from Ruby, Elixir takes the power of Erlang, and makes it accessible to even novice programmers. Elixir includes all of the most impressive features from it’s predecessor, such as the functional paradigm, hot-swapping of code, and fault-tolerance or the “let it crash” philosophy.</description></item><item><title>Open Source at Facebook</title><link>/events/2014-10-23-open-source-at-facebook/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2014-10-23-open-source-at-facebook/</guid><description>Thursday, 2014-10-23 at 7:00pm in Caldwell Labs 120, Patrick Shuff (an engineer at Facebook) will present &amp;ldquo;Open Source at Facebook&amp;rdquo;. Description follows:
Facebook serves requests for over 1.3 billion people every month. I will give a brief overview of our Traffic/CDN (e.g. images and videos) infrastructure and how open source software is core to being able to deliver all of those bits to the world every day!
Laptops are encouraged but not required, and as always, there will be pizza.</description></item><item><title>Love your Music and Movies again with Linux</title><link>/events/2014-10-16-love-your-music-and-movies-again-with-linux/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2014-10-16-love-your-music-and-movies-again-with-linux/</guid><description>Thursday, 2014-10-16 at 7:00pm in Caldwell Labs 120, Chris Wallace will present Love your Music and Movies again with Linux. Description follows:
The year is 2014: home theater PCs are all but extinct&amp;hellip; or are they? This talk will help you reinvigorate your media collection with a home media center, complete with intranet access and a killer frontend. We&amp;rsquo;ll cover some of the fun of Plex, XBMC, and MythTV. As a bonus, we&amp;rsquo;ll even show you what you can do with using a Raspberry Pi.</description></item><item><title>Personal Projects Lightning Talks</title><link>/events/2014-10-09-personal-projects/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2014-10-09-personal-projects/</guid><description>Hi everyone!
This Thursday, 2014-10-09 in Caldwell Labs 120, The Open Source Club at The Ohio State University will present Personal Projects.
This series of lightning talks will give an opportunity for members of The Open Source Club to show off the stuff that they&amp;rsquo;ve been making, whether at hackathons or in their spare time. Even class projects can be interesting.
The talk format is open to everyone, but if you want to 100% reserve space email meetings@opensource.</description></item><item><title>Zimbra: Open Source Mail and Groupware</title><link>/events/2014-10-02-zimbra-open-source-mail-and-groupware/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2014-10-02-zimbra-open-source-mail-and-groupware/</guid><description>This Thursday, 2014-10-02 in Caldwell Labs 120, William Osler will present Zimbra: Open Source Mail &amp;amp; Groupware. Description follows.
Email has been the core of how we communicate via the internet for longer than some of us have been alive, but in modern times can involve a complex interaction between various systems to get your message from point A to point B. But it doesn’t have to be hard. I’ll be going over Zimbra, an open source mail and groupware solution that you can host and run yourself.</description></item><item><title>Pure Data</title><link>/events/2014-09-25-pure-data/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2014-09-25-pure-data/</guid><description>Thursday, 2014/09/25 at 7:00pm in Caldwell Labs 120, Alex Fuhr will present Pure Data. Pure Data is an open source, minimal, and visual programming language for audio, graphic, and signal processing. This talk will start by covering the basic building blocks of the language, then dive deeper into the following topics:
Audio and waveform generation
The &amp;ldquo;data flow&amp;rdquo; model of communication
Helpful utilities
Graphical processing</description></item><item><title>Introduction to the Command Line</title><link>/events/2014-09-18-introduction-to-the-command-line/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2014-09-18-introduction-to-the-command-line/</guid><description>Thursday, 2014-09-18 at 7:00pm in Caldwell Labs 120, George Kvaratskhelia will present &amp;ldquo;Introduction to the Command Line&amp;rdquo;. This talk, geared toward beginners to the world of Unix and Unix-like systems, will cover the absolute basics of getting around and being productive in your Linux environment.
Topics covered should include (but not be limited to):
basic directory traversal file ownership and permissions file creation / deletion / rename basic editing Laptops are encouraged but not required, and as always, there will be pizza.</description></item><item><title>Wireless Security</title><link>/events/2014-09-11-wireless-security/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2014-09-11-wireless-security/</guid><description>This Thursday, 2014/09/11 at 7pm, in Caldwell Labs 120, Chris Wallace will present Wireless Security. In this talk, we will discuss different ways of penetrating wireless access points with the goal of explaining how security works in a wifi world. The takeaway from this is that, once you&amp;rsquo;re out there, you should be able to protect your wifi as best as possible. This talk is intended to be interactive, which means that there will be an access point on location that we&amp;rsquo;ll be attempting to gain access to.</description></item><item><title>Linux Installfest</title><link>/events/2014-09-04-linux-installfest/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2014-09-04-linux-installfest/</guid><description>Thursday, 2014-09-04 at 7pm in Caldwell Labs 120, Chris Wallace and the Open Source Club will present &amp;ldquo;Linux InstallFest&amp;rdquo;. We&amp;rsquo;ll be helping you to install GNU/Linux on your machines, and will be available to answer any questions you may have.
Overall, we would like you to not only have GNU/Linux installed, but also have a pretty good idea of the things you can do with it.
Laptops are always encouraged but not required, and as always, there will be pizza.</description></item><item><title>What is Open Source?</title><link>/events/2014-08-28-what-is-open-source/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2014-08-28-what-is-open-source/</guid><description>Thursday, 2014-08-28 at 7:00pm in Caldwell Labs (CL) 120, Chris Wallace and the Open Source Club will present our very first meeting of the 2014-2015 academic year, titled &amp;ldquo;What is Open Source&amp;rdquo;.
This meeting, geared toward beginners, gives an overview of the club including what we do and why we care. Additionally, this meeting is more social in nature with plenty of time to meet new people and network around.</description></item><item><title>Cracking the Data Encryption Standard</title><link>/events/2014-04-24-cracking-the-data-encryption-standard/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2014-04-24-cracking-the-data-encryption-standard/</guid><description>Thursday, April 24th 2014 in Caldwell Labs 120, C. Matthew Curtin will present &amp;ldquo;Cracking the Data Encryption Standard.&amp;rdquo;
Matt was one of the leaders of the DESCHALL project that cracked a message encrypted with the then-US-Government-Standard 56-bit DES using idle cycles of computers connected over the Internet. His book, Brute Force: Cracking the Data Encryption Standard, is the memoir of that project, and the presentation will give an inside look into one of the largest computations ever performed, forcing a change in US policy, and looking back and seeing how what happened then relates to the present policy issues regarding the relationship between the government and its citizenry online.</description></item><item><title>Anti-features, Free and Open Source Software, and Ethics</title><link>/events/2014-04-17-anti-features-free-and-open-source-software-and-ethics/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2014-04-17-anti-features-free-and-open-source-software-and-ethics/</guid><description>Thursday, 2014/04/17 at 7:00pm in Caldwell Labs 120, Owen King of the Department of Philosophy will present: Anti-features, Free and Open Source Software, and Ethics.
Abstract: DRM, spyware, adware, crippleware, backdoors. What do all these have in common? For starters, we usually prefer that they not be included in our software. More specifically, we can say that these are all examples of anti-features. Unfortunately, most ways people have tried to define &amp;lsquo;anti-feature&amp;rsquo; have been inadequate in some way.</description></item><item><title>Open Source Hardware (Arduino)</title><link>/events/2014-04-03-open-source-hardware-arduino/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2014-04-03-open-source-hardware-arduino/</guid><description>Thursday, April 3rd at 7:00PM in Caldwell Labs (CL) 120, Ben Rhoads will present Arduino and Open-Source Hardware. The first half of the meeting will discuss Arduino, an open-source physical computing platform based on a simple microcontroller board, and the second half of the meeting will be a PCB layout demonstration using Upverter. Upverter is the Github equivalent for circuitry. You can create a free Upverter account if you would like to follow along during the demonstration.</description></item><item><title>Bedrock Linux</title><link>/events/2014-03-27-bedrock-linux/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2014-03-27-bedrock-linux/</guid><description>This Thursday, May 27th at 7:00PM in Caldwell Labs (CL) 120, Daniel Thau and Brad Hollander will present Bedrock Linux. Bedrock Linux is a Linux distribution founded by Daniel with the aim of making most of the (often seemingly mutually-exclusive) benefits of various other Linux distributions available simultaneously and transparently. For example, if one would like a rock-solid stable base (for example, from Debian or a RHEL clone) yet still have easy access to cutting-edge packages (from, say, Arch Linux), Bedrock will provide a means to achieve this.</description></item><item><title>Raspberry Pi / Officer Nominations</title><link>/events/2014-03-20-raspberry-pi-officer-nominations/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2014-03-20-raspberry-pi-officer-nominations/</guid><description>This Thursday, 2014/03/20 at 7pm in Caldwell Labs (CL) 120, the Open Source Club will present Raspberry Pi, the arm powered $35 computer, available online and also at micro center.
This talk will cover getting started from scratch with the pi, and then we&amp;rsquo;ll dive into what club members have done with theirs.
Additionally, we will process officer nominations this meeting! Anyone interested in running for one of our positions (President / VP / Treasurer) should come to this meeting to get more information about the positions and what we do.</description></item><item><title>Securing Public Wireless Use: OpenVPN</title><link>/events/2014-03-06-securing-public-wireless-use-openvpn/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2014-03-06-securing-public-wireless-use-openvpn/</guid><description>This Thursday, 2014/03/06 in Caldwell Labs 120, Will Osler will present Securing Public Wireless Use: OpenVPN. With the prevalence of free public WiFi access in restaurants, shops, and venues across the city it&amp;rsquo;s important to know the risks associated with connecting &amp;ndash; and what you can do about it. This talk focuses on the dangers associated with using public non-encrypted WiFi, several ways to protect yourself and the advantages and disadvantages of several solutions.</description></item><item><title>Crypto Currencies</title><link>/events/2014-02-27-crypto-currencies/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2014-02-27-crypto-currencies/</guid><description>Greetings everyone, sorry for the late email this week.
This Thursday, 2014/02/27 at 7pm in Caldwell Labs 120, Chris Wallace of the Open Source Club will give a talk on crypto currencies.
The talk will cover different parts of how these currencies work, and will also touch on some of the controversies surrounding these currencies. Popular CCs include:
Bitcoin Litecoin Namecoin Dogecoin Laptops are encouraged but not required, and as always, there will be pizza.</description></item><item><title>OSC Goes to COLUG! (OpenStack)</title><link>/events/2014-02-20-osc-goes-to-colug-openstack/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2014-02-20-osc-goes-to-colug-openstack/</guid><description>Greetings Everyone,
This Thursday, 2014/02/20 at 7pm until 9pm at TechColumbus, the Central Ohio Linux Users Group and Red Hat will be presenting OpenStack. Heres info below:
Perry Myers from Red Hat will present OpenStack. He&amp;rsquo;ll demo installation, and provide an overview of the various OpenStack components: Keystone, Cinder, Glance, Neutron, Nova, Swift and more!
As always, feel free to bring with you any ailing or problematic systems for expert diagnosis (or destruction).</description></item><item><title>Init Discussions</title><link>/events/2014-02-13-init-discussions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2014-02-13-init-discussions/</guid><description>This Thursday, 2014/02/13 at 7:00pm in Caldwell Labs 120, The Open Source Club will have a discussion on Init Systems.
Init systems play an important role in starting modern unix-like operating systems, and recently they have been a point of discussion in the communities surrounding Linux distributions like debian.
Laptops are encouraged but not required and as always, there will be pizza.</description></item><item><title>Filesystems</title><link>/events/2014-02-06-filesystems/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2014-02-06-filesystems/</guid><description>This Thursday, February 6th at 7:00pm in Caldwell Labs 120, Paul Schellin will present &amp;ldquo;Filesystems&amp;rdquo;
This topic will cover:
A history on filesystems Examples of current and past FSs Virtual filesystems A custom-built filesystem anything else! Laptops are encouraged though not required, and as always, there will be pizza.</description></item><item><title>Resume Review</title><link>/events/2014-01-30-resume-review/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2014-01-30-resume-review/</guid><description>Hello!
This Thursday, January 30th at 7pm in Caldwell Labs 120, the Open Source Club will hold a resume review session with Brooksource. Bring your resume for an opportunity to get it read by recruiters to make sure you are ready for the S.W.E. career fair this Wednesday, February 5th. There will be gift cards and as always, there will be pizza. Brooksource is a firm specializing in project and supplemental support through contract employment, contract-to-hire labor employment, and direct placements.</description></item><item><title>Distributed Version Control Systems</title><link>/events/2014-01-23-distributed-version-control-systems/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2014-01-23-distributed-version-control-systems/</guid><description>Greetings!
This Thursday, January 23rd 2014 at 7:00PM in Caldwell Labs 133(note the change), Daniel Thau will be giving a presentation on Distributed Version Control Systems (DVCS). DVCSs are distributed systems which keep track of software revisions. These are usually, but not necessarily, used to manage programming projects. Daniel will go over the idea behind a DVCS, as well as some of the stuff going on under the hood in one of them (git).</description></item><item><title>Virtualization</title><link>/events/2014-01-16-virtualization/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2014-01-16-virtualization/</guid><description>Greetings!
This Thursday, January 16th at 7pm in Caldwell Labs 120, Chris Wallace will present &amp;ldquo;Virtual Servers: An introduction to virtualization in linux&amp;rdquo;.
I&amp;rsquo;ll try to cover some of the common virtual server options in linux such as:
KVM Xen OpenVZ Virtualbox and other solutions, as well as practical situations and reasoning for using a virtual server over a physical server.
Hope to see you there!</description></item><item><title>Welcome Back</title><link>/events/2014-01-09-welcome-back/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2014-01-09-welcome-back/</guid><description>Hello everyone!
I hope everyones break (as well as additional days off) have been swell. To celebrate, this Thursday, January 9 at 7pm in Caldwell Labs 120 we will be having an open-ended meeting with open discussion. To make things cooler, we will have nice pizza (adriadicos) and a raspberry pi and arduino to play around on.
This meeting will also be where we plan future meetings for the semester, so come with any ideas you may have!</description></item><item><title>vim</title><link>/events/2013-11-21-vim/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2013-11-21-vim/</guid><description>This Thursday, 2013/11/21 at 7:00PM in Caldwell Labs 120, Daniel Thau will present a tour of advanced Vim functionality. Prior Vim experience is not required. Even if you do not use or like Vim, you may still get some useful ideas to incorporate into your workflow with other editors/IDEs. A potential (and incomplete) list of topics is below.
EDIT: The topics covered are below.
The majority of the things below can be :help&amp;rsquo;d.</description></item><item><title>Developer Tools</title><link>/events/2013-11-14-developer-tools/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2013-11-14-developer-tools/</guid><description>This Thursday, 2013/14/11 at 7:00pm in Caldwell Labs 120, Maxim Kim will be presenting various developer tools (30min - 1 hour). Text editors, IDEs, standalone utilities help you improve your productivity and reduce the amount of tedious and repetitive work. The presentation will cover popular choices such as Emacs, Eclipse, and IntelliJ, as well as some nice features that they provide. Slides will be here.
Laptops are encouraged, but not required, and as always, there will be pizza.</description></item><item><title>LAN Party</title><link>/events/2013-11-09-lan-party/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2013-11-09-lan-party/</guid><description>Hey everyone,
This Saturday, November 09 at 10am until 10pm in the Ohio Union Senate Chamber Room, the Ohio State Open Source Club will have a LAN party.
Come on out if you&amp;rsquo;re interested in such games as Team Fortress 2, Teeworlds, Armegatron, and more!
We will provide infrastructure, food, and of course soda.
Hope to see you there!</description></item><item><title>Internet Privacy and Anonymization</title><link>/events/2013-11-07-internet-privacy-and-anonymization/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2013-11-07-internet-privacy-and-anonymization/</guid><description>Hey everyone, sorry for the late email!
This Thursday 2013/11/07, at 7:00pm in Caldwell Labs 120 we will be discussing Internet Privacy, as well as tools that can keep you anonymous on the Internet. Topics will include Tor, Firefox Extensions, and Darknets, as well as a discussion on technical privacy. Laptops are encouraged, and as always, there will be pizza.</description></item><item><title>JavaScript</title><link>/events/2013-10-24-javascript/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2013-10-24-javascript/</guid><description>This Thursday, 2013/24/10 at 7:00pm in Caldwell Labs 120, Maxim Kim will be presenting JavaScript. This will be about 40 min long. It will be a high level overview of the language with some examples covering both server and client side. Slides can be found here.
As always, there will be pizza.</description></item><item><title>Android</title><link>/events/2013-10-17-android/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2013-10-17-android/</guid><description>This Thursday, 2013/17/10 at 7:00pm in Caldwell Labs 120, Brad Hollander (slackbyte) will be presenting the Android operating system. Android is a Linux based, open source operating system, owned by Google, for phones and tablets. While key concepts of Android app development will be discussed, this presentation will be primarily focused on how the operating system works &amp;ldquo;under the hood&amp;rdquo; and the way that it leverages Linux for its security and stability.</description></item><item><title>Security and Encryption</title><link>/events/2013-10-10-security-and-encryption/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2013-10-10-security-and-encryption/</guid><description>This Thursday, 2013/10/10 at 7:00pm in Caldwell Labs 120, The Ohio State Open Source Club will present &amp;ldquo;Security and Encryption&amp;rdquo;. This talk will consist of different members presenting on a variety of topics in the world of personal encryption and protecting your privacy. If you have an interest in security, or cryptographic systems as they apply computing, this is probably the talk for you.
Laptops are encouraged, but not required, and as always, there will be pizza.</description></item><item><title>AWK</title><link>/events/2013-10-03-awk/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2013-10-03-awk/</guid><description>This Thursday, 2013/10/03 in Caldwell Labs 120, Daniel Thau will be presenting the AWK programming language. AWK is an interpreted programming language which excels at text processing and quick-and-dirty one-liners. It is part of the POSIX standard and will thus be found on just about every unix system, including exceedingly minimal ones. AWK has a number of relatively unique aspects that can make it quite enjoyable to use - for its target use, an AWK program is often significantly smaller than almost every other language.</description></item><item><title>Desktop Applications</title><link>/events/2013-09-26-desktop-applications/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2013-09-26-desktop-applications/</guid><description>This Thursday, 2013/09/26 at 7pm, in Caldwell Labs 120, we will have multiple speakers presenting their favorite desktop applications. Explore the open source apps that are great for office productivity, music, movies, image and video editing, teleconferencing. If you want to talk about your favorite app, let us know at meetings@opensource.osu.edu
Additionally, we will be doing initial signups for the Hackathon that&amp;rsquo;s been mentioned at this meeting. Also, we will be doing account requests for the Open Source Club computers too.</description></item><item><title>Wireless Security</title><link>/events/2013-09-19-wireless-security/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2013-09-19-wireless-security/</guid><description>This Thursday, 2013/09/19 at 7pm, in Caldwell Labs 120, Chris Wallace will present Wireless Security. In this talk, we will discuss different ways of penetrating wireless access points with the goal of explaining how security works in a wifi world. The takeaway from this is that, once you&amp;rsquo;re out there, you should be able to protect your wifi as best as possible. This talk is intended to be interactive, which means that there will be an access point on location that we&amp;rsquo;ll be attempting to gain access to.</description></item><item><title>Overview of Web Servers</title><link>/events/2013-09-12-overview-of-web-servers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2013-09-12-overview-of-web-servers/</guid><description>This Thursday, September 12, in Caldwell Labs 120, Matt Meinwald will discuss Free HTTP servers, including Apache, Lighttpd, and Nginx. He will go over some of the benefits and limitations of each, and also compare configuration. Some command-line knowledge would be helpful, but no prior web server experience is needed. You will not necessarily walk out an expert on web servers, but by the end of the meeting, you should have the resources to set up a basic web server.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Command Line</title><link>/events/2013-09-05-introduction-to-command-line/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2013-09-05-introduction-to-command-line/</guid><description>This Thursday, September 5th at 7pm in Caldwell Labs 120, Brad Hollander will present &amp;ldquo;Introduction to the Command Line&amp;rdquo;. This presentation/lecture is geared toward beginner users of the GNU/Linux OS, with an end goal of getting participants comfortable in a shell environment. Questions will be welcome at any time throughout the presentation as well.
Laptops are encouraged, but not required, and as always, there will be pizza.</description></item><item><title>Linux InstallFest and Introduction</title><link>/events/2013-08-29-linux-installfest-and-introduction/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2013-08-29-linux-installfest-and-introduction/</guid><description>Thursday 2013/08/29 at 7pm in Dreese Lab 266, Chris Wallace and the Open Source Club will present &amp;ldquo;Linux InstallFest and Introduction&amp;rdquo;. This meeting will consist of two different hour-long blocks. In the first section, we will provide installation media for different distributions of the GNU/Linux operating system, with seasoned members present to help get those interested installed. In the second hour, we will provide an introduction to the GNU/Linux command line environment.</description></item><item><title>What is Open Source</title><link>/events/2013-08-22-what-is-open-source/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2013-08-22-what-is-open-source/</guid><description>This Thursday 2013/08/22 at 7pm in Dreese Labs 266, Chris Wallace will present our very first meeting of the 2013-2014 academic year &amp;ldquo;What is Open Source&amp;rdquo;. As in the past, this first meeting will serve as an introduction to what the term open source means and is about, as well as what we do in this club. We will also discuss current privacy issues (PRISM and friends), and free/open source alternatives to popular products.</description></item><item><title>End of the Year</title><link>/events/2013-04-18-end-of-the-year/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2013-04-18-end-of-the-year/</guid><description>This Thursday, 2013/04/18 at 7:00pm in Dreese Labs 369, the Ohio State Open Source Club will be having an End of the Year meeting. We will be having some nice(er) pizza and drinks, and have an open discussion. This can be everything from Free software and RMS to a personal project you have been working on and want to share, it&amp;rsquo;s all up to you.
As always, all meetings are open to the public.</description></item><item><title>Security and Elections</title><link>/events/2013-04-11-security-and-elections/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2013-04-11-security-and-elections/</guid><description>This Thursday, 2013/04/11 at 7:00pm in Dreese Labs 369, the Ohio State Open Source Club will be presenting Security. This will be a talk consisting of multiple members going up and speaking about different topics in the open source world of security.
Additionally, elections will be taking place at this meeting. If anyone would still like to run, please email elections@opensource.osu.edu with a quick blurb about what you&amp;rsquo;re running for.</description></item><item><title>Python</title><link>/events/2013-03-28-python/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2013-03-28-python/</guid><description>This Thursday, 2013/03/28 at 7pm in Dreese Labs 369, Edward Powell will be presenting an introduction to the Python programming language. The presentation will be a follow-along crash course in the language. It will cover the basics of the language and key parts of the standard library, as well as some interesting third-party libraries. It will also include some of the cooler advanced features, and some interesting ways you can use Python to make quick and easy solutions to problems.</description></item><item><title>Richard Stallman visiting OSU</title><link>/events/2013-03-25-richard-stallman-visiting-osu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2013-03-25-richard-stallman-visiting-osu/</guid><description>This Monday, Richard Stallman is visiting OSU as a guest lecturer in the computer science department. His presentation will be at 4 pm in the Journalism Building, room 300, and the lecture is open to the public.
Attached are some pictures taken. All photos are licensed CC-BY-ND.
Ben Keith took the photo of Saint iGNUcius, while David Ritz took the group picture, and the pictures of the poster.
One of our members also uploaded a recording of the talk (also ogg).</description></item><item><title>Shell Scripting</title><link>/events/2013-03-21-shell-scripting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2013-03-21-shell-scripting/</guid><description>Thursday, March 21nd, 2013 in Dreese Labs 369, Daniel Thau will present an introduction to POSIX Bourne shell scripting. A general familiarity with a UNIX command line environment and UNIX utilities (grep, sed, awk, etc) will be useful but not required. If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever expressed interest in making your life easier at the command line, this could be the talk for you.
Additionally, elections will be taking place at our second to last meeting of the semester (2013/04/11).</description></item><item><title>Distributed Version Control</title><link>/events/2013-03-07-distributed-version-control/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2013-03-07-distributed-version-control/</guid><description>This Thursday, 2013/03/07 at 7pm in Dreese Labs 369, the Ohio State Open Source Club will be presenting &amp;ldquo;Distributed Version Control v1&amp;rdquo; This meeting will be presented by Paul Schwendenman.
The meeting will lightly touch on some made-up history of version control and then information and examples related to bazaar, git and mercurial. At the end of this meeting you should be able to comfortably work with a distributed version control system.</description></item><item><title>Raspberry Pi</title><link>/events/2013-02-28-raspberry-pi/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2013-02-28-raspberry-pi/</guid><description>This Thursday, 2013/02/28 at 7pm in Dreese Labs 369, the Ohio State Open Source Club will be presenting &amp;ldquo;Raspberry Pi: All that you can do for $35.&amp;rdquo; This meeting will consist at first with a presentation by Chris Wallace into what this little guy is all about, followed by a series consisting primarily of members sharing their experiences with the Raspberry Pi, a $35 computer platform about the size of a credit card (raspberrypi.</description></item><item><title>Willie the IRC bot</title><link>/events/2013-02-21-willie-the-irc-bot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2013-02-21-willie-the-irc-bot/</guid><description>This Thursday, 2013/02/21 at 7pm in Dreese Labs 369, Edward Powell will be presenting on the Willie IRC bot. The bot has all sorts of cool features, like the ability to retrieve your time and weather, or the upvotes on a Reddit post, all from within an IRC channel. Even better, it&amp;rsquo;s designed to make it easy for you to write your own features, with a simple and featureful API. Both the API and the included features will be covered, along with some information about how the bot works behind the scenes.</description></item><item><title>Getting the Most Battery out of Your Laptop</title><link>/events/2013-02-14-getting-the-most-battery-out-of-your-laptop/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2013-02-14-getting-the-most-battery-out-of-your-laptop/</guid><description>This Thursday, 2013/02/14 at 7pm in Dreese Labs 369, Daniel Thau will be presenting techniques to maximize battery life on a Linux laptop. With the techniques which will be presented, it is not unusual for laptops to have battery lives that actually outlast manufacturer&amp;rsquo;s advertised specifications; for example, Daniel&amp;rsquo;s Lenovo x230 with a 94Wh battery tends to last upwards of 12 hours in real-world conditions. If you really love your laptop, and want to show it how much you care this Valentine&amp;rsquo;s day, this presentation will show you how to treat it right.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Android Development by Harris</title><link>/events/2013-02-07-introduction-to-android-development-by-harris/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2013-02-07-introduction-to-android-development-by-harris/</guid><description>Hello everyone!
This Thursday, 2013/02/07 at 7pm in Dreese Labs 369, Hussain Frosh of Harris will be presenting an introduction to development for Android. This talk will assume that the user will be starting from scratch, with no prior knowledge of developing for Android. Java experience is encouraged, but not required for the scope of this talk.
We recommend bringing a laptop, as the goal for this presentation is to have all participants set up and comfortable with the development environment for Android.</description></item><item><title>GIMP Image Editing</title><link>/events/2013-01-31-gimp-image-editing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2013-01-31-gimp-image-editing/</guid><description>This Thursday at 7 pm, in Dreese Lab 369, Brian Swaney will teach us GIMP image editing techniques. The presentation will be interactive and encourage audience participation, so you should bring a laptop with GIMP already installed to follow along. Some techniques covered may include cloning/healing, layer masking, fine selections, and basic image transformations. Some more advanced techniques may be covered if time allows, just to show that GIMP can live up to the same standard as other editors whose names are withheld due to trademark licensing concerns, but no prior experience is required.</description></item><item><title>IRC</title><link>/events/2013-01-24-irc/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2013-01-24-irc/</guid><description>This Thursday, 2013/01/24 at 7:00pm (EST, -5G MT) in Dreese Labs 369, Michael Yanovich will take you upon a journey of exploring the depths of irc. He will be covering: what IRC is, what IRC is used for, and most importantly how to interface with IRC. From general observations, it appears that many in the club use IRC and many more would like to participate in the IRC channel #osuosc on Libera.</description></item><item><title>The Command Line</title><link>/events/2013-01-17-the-command-line/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2013-01-17-the-command-line/</guid><description>Hello everyone!
This Thursday, January 17th, at 7pm in Dreese Lab 369, Brad Hollander will be presenting The Command Line. This will serve as an introduction to basic and advanced features of the command line, as well as tools, utilities, and applications that are available. Additionally, there will be a short introduction to vim near the end from Daniel Thau.
The hope is that by the end you should be more successful and know practical tools relating to the command line in Linux/Unix.</description></item><item><title>Open Source Operating Systems and Semester Planning</title><link>/events/2013-01-10-open-source-operating-systems-and-semester-planning/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2013-01-10-open-source-operating-systems-and-semester-planning/</guid><description>This week, Thursday 2013/01/10 at 7pm in Dreese 369, The Ohio State University Open Source Club will be presenting Free and Open Source Operating Systems- An Overview, introduction, and discussion. Members of the club will present different open source operating systems, with the end goal of making everyone more knowledgeable on the variety of distributions out there.
If you don&amp;rsquo;t use Linux, BSD, or otherwise, this could be the time to see where your interests are, and what works for you!</description></item><item><title>Personal Projects</title><link>/events/2012-11-29-personal-projects/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2012-11-29-personal-projects/</guid><description>Hello everyone!
This Thursday, November 29 at 7:00pm in Dreese Labs 266, The Ohio State University Open Source Club will present &amp;ldquo;Personal Projects.&amp;rdquo;
This talk will have members of the club giving small bits on what they are doing in their spare time. If you have interest in speaking, please email me at wallace.586@osu.edu with your topic.
Talks will be limited to 5 minutes at a time, with the hope of getting to everyone with interest in speaking to have their time.</description></item><item><title>No Meeting this Week</title><link>/events/2012-11-22-no-meeting-this-week/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2012-11-22-no-meeting-this-week/</guid><description>Due to the Thanksgiving holiday on Thursday, we will not have a meeting this week. The next meeting is November 29th. More details on that upcoming meeting will be posted soon.</description></item><item><title>Ardunio</title><link>/events/2012-11-15-ardunio/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2012-11-15-ardunio/</guid><description>Ryan Karason will be demonstrating open source hardware. The purpose of the lecture is to discuss the basic principles of electricity as applied to circuitry and to introduce the open hardware prototyping platform created by Arduino. If you are interested in getting involved in making your own circuits or better understanding others' circuits so you can hack them, show up this Thursday; November 15, 2012 at 7PM in 266 Dreese Laboratory.</description></item><item><title>Forensic Analysis</title><link>/events/2012-11-08-forensic-analysis/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2012-11-08-forensic-analysis/</guid><description>This week&amp;rsquo;s meeting will include a presentation by C. Matthew Curtin, the first faculty advisor of our club as well as a Lecturer in the Department of Computer Science and Engineering. He is the founder of Interhack, a computer expert firm with offices in Columbus and Chicago. With clients across North America, Interhack consults in high-stakes situations including data breaches, mission-critical system failure, and forensic analysis of computer systems and data in complex litigation.</description></item><item><title>Open Stack</title><link>/events/2012-11-01-open-stack/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2012-11-01-open-stack/</guid><description>This Thursday, November 1st at 7:00PM in Dreese Labs 266, Joel Friedly will be presenting an overview of OpenStack.
OpenStack is an open source counterpart to the software behind Amazon Web Services (EC2, S3, etc.). Since being started in 2010 by NASA and Rackspace Hosting, more than 150 companies have joined the project, including AMD, Intel, Canonical, SUSE Linux, Red Hat, Cisco, Dell, HP, IBM and Yahoo!. It is free open source software released under the terms of the Apache License.</description></item><item><title>Advanced Overview of Vim</title><link>/events/2012-10-25-advanced-overview-of-vim/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2012-10-25-advanced-overview-of-vim/</guid><description>Thursday, October 25th at 7:00PM in Dreese Labs 266, Daniel Thau will be presenting an overview of various advanced functionality for the Vim text editor. This talk is not intended to fully educate the audience on the use of the discussed functionality so much as make the audience aware of the advanced functionality Vim has to offer in order to have something to work towards. Comfort with the basics of Vim would be useful but not required.</description></item><item><title>What NOT to do with your F/OSS Operating System</title><link>/events/2012-10-18-what-not-to-do-with-your-f-oss-operating-system/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2012-10-18-what-not-to-do-with-your-f-oss-operating-system/</guid><description>Hey everyone,
This Thursday, 2012/10/18 at 7pm in Dreese Labs 266, The Ohio State Open Source Club will be presenting &amp;ldquo;What NOT to do with your F/OSS Operating System.&amp;rdquo;
This talk will be done a little more casual, with members sharing disaster stories of what they have done to their operating systems.
I encourage everyone to participate, I just ask that you email me back with these three fields so that I may make you a slide:</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Vim</title><link>/events/2012-10-11-introduction-to-vim/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2012-10-11-introduction-to-vim/</guid><description>Thursday, October 11th at 7:00PM in Dreese Labs 264, Daniel Thau will be presenting an introduction to the Vim text editor. Vim is known for having a difficult learning curve, but for many of those who do any appreciable amount of work editing text (such as, but not limited to, programming), the benefits can far outweigh the costs.
In the past, Daniel&amp;rsquo;s presentations on Vim have attempted to provide benefit, for everyone from those completely new to Vim to more experienced users.</description></item><item><title>Open Source and Your Music</title><link>/events/2012-10-04-open-source-and-your-music/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2012-10-04-open-source-and-your-music/</guid><description>Hello everyone!
This Thursday, October 4th, at 7pm in Dreese Labs 264, Chris Wallace will be presenting &amp;ldquo;Open Source and Your Music.&amp;rdquo;
The presentation should cover:
Media Players Audio Formats Music Management Licensing Issues &amp;hellip; and more!
As always, there will be pizza.</description></item><item><title>Autumn LAN Party</title><link>/events/2012-09-22-autumn-lan-party/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2012-09-22-autumn-lan-party/</guid><description>Good news everyone!
This Saturday, September 22 2012, from 12:00pm - 10:00pm in the Ohio Union Interfaith Prayer and Reflection Room, The Ohio State Open Source Club will present it&amp;rsquo;s first LAN Party of the autumn semester. Come out and join, meeting Open Source Club members and playing games (both open and closed source). The games include:
Minecraft Team Fortress 2 Counter-Strike Starcraft (I / II) Warsow Teeworlds &amp;hellip; and anything else that we decide while we are there!</description></item><item><title>Blender</title><link>/events/2012-09-20-blender/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2012-09-20-blender/</guid><description>This Thursday, September 20 at 7:00 pm in Dreese Labs 266, Steffan Pease will be presenting the Blender 3D Computer Graphics Software. Blender is a powerful open source application used for creating animated films, visual effects, interactive 3D applications or video games (source). This will be interactive, as we will be making an example mesh, and texturing it with ambient occlusion and color.
Please come prepared with blender (&amp;gt;2.5) installed, a 3-button mouse, and a keyboard with a number pad if you wish to follow along.</description></item><item><title>Emacs</title><link>/events/2012-09-13-emacs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2012-09-13-emacs/</guid><description>This Thursday, September 13th at 7:00 pm in Dreese 266, Maxim Kim will be presenting the Emacs text editor.
GNU Emacs is a famous text editor proved to be extremely versatile and powerful.
This presentation will have two parts:
An overview of Emacs and its features (30-40 min) Question and answer session (0-? min) Please, come EARLY, otherwise you can miss a half of the overview. A brief copy of the overview can be found at emacs-tutorial.</description></item><item><title>Android</title><link>/events/2012-09-06-android/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2012-09-06-android/</guid><description>This Thursday, September 6th at 7:00 pm in Dreese 266, Brad Hollander will be presenting the Android operating system. Android is Google&amp;rsquo;s open-source mobile operating system for smartphones and tablets, built on top of a customized Linux kernel. Applications are written in Java and are compiled to be run on the Dalvik virtual machine. All are welcome and as always, there will be pizza.</description></item><item><title>Wi-Fi Hacking</title><link>/events/2012-08-30-wi-fi-hacking/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2012-08-30-wi-fi-hacking/</guid><description>I, Michael Yanovich, will be covering Wi-Fi Hacking on 2012/08/30 at 7:00pm (20120830T1900-0400 for those who love ISO8601 compliant dates) in Dreese Labs 266. What I want people to walk away from this talk with is the knowledge of how to try to protect their Access Points (AP) the best they can with currently available technology. I will start off with a basic introduction into simple Electricity and Magnetism (E&amp;amp;M) and quickly move into some of the layers of the OSI Model of networking involved.</description></item><item><title>First Meeting: What is Open Source?</title><link>/events/2012-08-23-first-meeting-what-is-open-source/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2012-08-23-first-meeting-what-is-open-source/</guid><description>Thursday, August 23rd at 7:00 PM in Dreese Labs room 266, The Ohio State University Open Source Club will have its first meeting of the 2012-2013 academic year. Paul Schwendenman, this year&amp;rsquo;s president, will be giving an introduction to what it means for something to be Open Source- hopefully helping to explain to any potential new members what the club is really about.
As always, pizza will be provided.</description></item><item><title>Summer Meetups</title><link>/events/2012-08-17-summer-meetups/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2012-08-17-summer-meetups/</guid><description>This week&amp;rsquo;s meetup will be at Mad Mex on Friday 2012/08/17 at 7:00pm. Mad Mex is located at 1542 N. High St.
&amp;ndash; Michael</description></item><item><title>SystemTap</title><link>/events/2012-08-16-systemtap/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2012-08-16-systemtap/</guid><description>SystemTap is a scripting language for your kernel. It allows for profiling or otherwise analyzing a running system, both at the kernel and userspace levels. I will start my talk by reviewing some of the other profiling and debugging tools available on a Linux system, then will illustrate how SystemTap can do all of that and a whole lot more.</description></item><item><title>Personal Projects</title><link>/events/2012-05-31-personal-projects/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2012-05-31-personal-projects/</guid><description>Thursday, May 31st at 7:00PM in Dreese 369, We will be presenting personal projects which is my favorite meeting. So come with your projects in hand and ready to show off and we will get through as many as possible.</description></item><item><title>Bedrock Linux</title><link>/events/2012-05-24-bedrock-linux/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2012-05-24-bedrock-linux/</guid><description>Thursday, May 24th at 7:00PM in Dreese 369, Daniel Thau will be presenting Bedrock Linux. Bedrock Linux is a Linux distribution created by Daniel with the aim of making most of the (often seemingly mutually-exclusive) benefits of various other Linux distributions available simultaneously and transparently. For example, if one would like a rock-solid stable base (for example, from Debian or a RHEL clone) yet still have easy access to cutting-edge packages (from, say, Arch Linux), Bedrock will provide a means to achieve this.</description></item><item><title>Elections, LaTeX, and LAN party</title><link>/events/2012-05-17-elections-latex-and-lan-party/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2012-05-17-elections-latex-and-lan-party/</guid><description>Elections for the OSU Open Source Club officer positions are currently planned for May 17th, 2012. They will take place in the normal meeting room (Dreese 369) and at the normal time (7:00PM EDT). If the date does not work for you and you are a voting club member (ie, you are a student and have attended at least one meeting prior to the vote), please contact the club offers as soon as possible and we will see what we can do.</description></item><item><title>OSC Spring LAN</title><link>/events/2012-05-12-osc-spring-lan/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2012-05-12-osc-spring-lan/</guid><description>The OSC will be hosting its second LAN of the academic year on May 12th, 2012.
Due to difficulties scheduling, it will start at 2:00PM and run until 11:30PM (ie, 9.5 hours) in the Ohio Union&amp;rsquo;s Interfaith Prayer and Reflection room. Bring Your Own Computer.</description></item><item><title>Python</title><link>/events/2012-05-10-python/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2012-05-10-python/</guid><description>This Thursday, will be a presentation on Python. This presentation will cover many of the basics and bring people up to speed of creating applications in the language. The crash course into Python&amp;rsquo;s basics will be &amp;ldquo;follow along&amp;rdquo; and questions are encouraged. The later half of the presentation will be presenting clever and nifty ways to accomplish various tasks that can be done in Python that are easier than building in other languages.</description></item><item><title>Android</title><link>/events/2012-05-03-android/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2012-05-03-android/</guid><description>Thursday, May 3rd at 7PM in Dreese 369, Brad Hollander will be presenting the Android operating system. Android is Google&amp;rsquo;s open-source mobile operating system for smartphones and tablets, built on top of a customized Linux kernel. Applications are written in Java and are compiled to be run on the Dalvik virtual machine.</description></item><item><title>This Week In Slashdot</title><link>/events/2012-04-26-this-week-in-slashdot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2012-04-26-this-week-in-slashdot/</guid><description>Thursday, April 26th at 7PM in Caldwell 369, Alex Lingo will be presenting an old club favorite known as &amp;ldquo;This Week in Slashdot&amp;rdquo;. Slashdot (commonly abbreviated as /.) is a website located at http://slashdot.org that deals in news for the nerdy. Readers submit articles which are then accepted or rejected by editors and then published on the site. From there, the readers have huge discussions about every aspect of the article which can be very funny/interesting/insightful/etc and oft prove to be a very good read.</description></item><item><title>Blender 3D Modeling &amp; Short Films</title><link>/events/2012-04-19-blender-3d-modeling-and-short-films/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2012-04-19-blender-3d-modeling-and-short-films/</guid><description>Thursday, April 19th at 7:00PM in Dreese 369, Alex Lingo will demonstrating the basic usage of the Blender 3D modeling/rendering program. Blender is an powerful open-source application that is as powerful as professional 3D modeling packages, and has been used to create commercial and open-source 3D films. Several of the Open Movie Project films will be shown during the presentation!
Please come prepared with a 3-button mouse and a keyboard with a number pad if you wish to follow along.</description></item><item><title>Sage Mathematics</title><link>/events/2012-04-12-sage-mathematics/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2012-04-12-sage-mathematics/</guid><description>On Thursday the 12th, in Dreese Lab room 369, Daniel Thau will present the Sage mathematics program. Sage is intended to be an open source alternative to software such as Magma, Maple, Mathematica and Matlab. Based around Python, it is quite pleasant to script and surprising capable.</description></item><item><title>Portable Unix Shell Scripting</title><link>/events/2012-04-05-portable-unix-shell-scripting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2012-04-05-portable-unix-shell-scripting/</guid><description>Thursday, April 5th 2012 at 7:00PM in Dreese Lab room 359, Daniel Thau will present on Portable Unix Shell Scripting. This presentation will partially depend on last quarter&amp;rsquo;s Unix Utility talk, but if you missed it you should still be fine.</description></item><item><title>Arduino and Open Source Hardware</title><link>/events/2012-03-29-arduino-and-open-source-hardware/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2012-03-29-arduino-and-open-source-hardware/</guid><description>THIS WEEK IN OPEN SOURCE!:
Ryan Karason will be teaching on open source hardware. The purpose of the lecture is to discuss the basic principles of electricity as applied to circuitry and to introduce the open hardware prototyping platform created by Arduino. If you are interested in getting involved in making your own circuits or better understanding others' circuits so you can hack them, show up this Thursday; March 29, 1012 at 7PM in 266 Dreese Laboratory.</description></item><item><title>That's What She Said and Planning</title><link>/events/2012-03-08-thats-what-she-said-and-planning/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2012-03-08-thats-what-she-said-and-planning/</guid><description>I apologize for the late meeting topic announcement, but there were some unexpected delays.
Thursday, March 8th at 7:00PM in Dreese 266 Joel Friedly will present on a project he was working on for a class. For a lab in his Python class, he built a simple Bayes network-based text classifier to identify That&amp;rsquo;s What She Said jokes in conversation transcripts. This will be added to Jenni, the Open Source Club&amp;rsquo;s IRC bot, so that she can make jokes at appropriate times in conversation.</description></item><item><title>Window Managers</title><link>/events/2012-03-01-window-managers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2012-03-01-window-managers/</guid><description>Thursday, March 1st at 7:00PM, various club members will be presenting window managers and desktop environments for X11. If you&amp;rsquo;ve never used anything but the default interface that comes with your Linux distribution and are interested in trying something new out, this should be right up your alley. If you&amp;rsquo;ve got a favorite, obscure window manager and you want to help spread the word, here&amp;rsquo;s your chance.
Currently, the following are more or less taken(/assigned):</description></item><item><title>Personal Projects</title><link>/events/2012-02-23-personal-projects/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2012-02-23-personal-projects/</guid><description>Thursday, February 23rd at 7:00PM in Dreese 266 various club members will be presenting personal projects. If you&amp;rsquo;re working on anything, feel free to bring it in to show off!</description></item><item><title>Introduction to GIMP Image Editing</title><link>/events/2012-02-16-introduction-to-gimp-image-editing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2012-02-16-introduction-to-gimp-image-editing/</guid><description>This Thursday at 7:00PM, in Dreese Lab room 266, Brian Swaney will be teaching us the basics of GIMP image editing. This presentation primarily will focus basic tools including but not limited to cloning/healing, layer masking, fine selections, and basic image transformations. To demonstrate that GIMP is on the same playing field as other proprietary and expensive image editors, some more advanced techniques may also be discussed if time allows. The talk is interactive, and use of a laptop with GIMP already installed is encouraged, but no prior experience with image editors is necessary.</description></item><item><title>The Shibboleth Project and Web Authentication at OSU</title><link>/events/2012-02-09-the-shibboleth-project-and-web-authentication-at-osu/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2012-02-09-the-shibboleth-project-and-web-authentication-at-osu/</guid><description>This Thursday at 7:00PM, in Dreese Lab room 266, Scott Cantor will be presenting on OSU&amp;rsquo;s central web-based authentication system, Shibboleth. Many of Ohio State&amp;rsquo;s web-based applications and services rely on this open source project for authentication of students and employees and to obtain information about those users for personalization or limiting access to authorized users.
Shibboleth is primarily based on an open standard called SAML that allows for authentication of users from multiple organizations to services running at different organizations, a security model called &amp;ldquo;federated identity&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Unix Command-Line Utilities</title><link>/events/2012-02-02-unix-command-line-utilities/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2012-02-02-unix-command-line-utilities/</guid><description>Thursday, February 2nd at 7:00PM in Dreese 266 Daniel Thau will be presenting Unix CLI Utilities such as grep, sed and awk. These tools are present on every Unix machine, and so if one ever finds him or herself on someone else&amp;rsquo;s Unix box without their language of choice, her or she can always fall back to these tools. Moreover, they&amp;rsquo;re quite good at manipulating text - the fundamental necessity for managing a Unix system.</description></item><item><title>Haskell: Part III</title><link>/events/2012-01-26-haskell-part-iii/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2012-01-26-haskell-part-iii/</guid><description>Thursday January 26th, 2012 Dreese Lab 266
Haskell is an advanced purely-functional programming language. An open-source product of more than twenty years of cutting-edge research, it allows rapid development of robust, concise, correct software. With strong support for integration with other languages, built-in concurrency and parallelism, debuggers, profilers, rich libraries and an active community, Haskell makes it easier to produce flexible, maintainable, high-quality software.
Haskell.org Continuing the series on introductory Haskell programming we will talk about abstractions common to everyday Haskell.</description></item><item><title>Haskell: Part III: Winter Resistance Edition: Snow and Freezing Rain Will Not Stop Us (neither will dry, 50F weather)</title><link>/events/2012-01-26-haskell-part-iii-winter-resistance-edition-snow-and-freezing-rain-will-not-stop-us-neither-will-dry-50f-weather/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2012-01-26-haskell-part-iii-winter-resistance-edition-snow-and-freezing-rain-will-not-stop-us-neither-will-dry-50f-weather/</guid><description>Thursday January 26, 2012
Dreese Lab 266
Haskell is an advanced purely-functional programming language. An open-source product of more than twenty years of cutting-edge research, it allows rapid development of robust, concise, correct software. With strong support for integration with other languages, built-in concurrency and parallelism, debuggers, profilers, rich libraries and an active community, Haskell makes it easier to produce flexible, maintainable, high-quality software.
&amp;ndash; Haskell.org
Continuing the series on introductory Haskell programming we will talk about abstractions common to everyday Haskell.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Haskell Part B</title><link>/events/2012-01-19-introduction-to-haskell-part-b/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2012-01-19-introduction-to-haskell-part-b/</guid><description>Introduction to Haskell Part B Dreese 266 7pm Thursday Jan 19 2012
Haskell is an advanced purely-functional programming language. An open-source product of more than twenty years of cutting-edge research, it allows rapid development of robust, concise, correct software. With strong support for integration with other languages, built-in concurrency and parallelism, debuggers, profilers, rich libraries and an active community, Haskell makes it easier to produce flexible, maintainable, high-quality software.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Haskell Part 0</title><link>/events/2012-01-12-introduction-to-haskell-part-0/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2012-01-12-introduction-to-haskell-part-0/</guid><description>Introduction to Haskell Part 0 Dreese 266 7pm Thursday Jan 12 2012
Haskell is an advanced purely-functional programming language. An open-source product of more than twenty years of cutting-edge research, it allows rapid development of robust, concise, correct software. With strong support for integration with other languages, built-in concurrency and parallelism, debuggers, profilers,rich libraries and an active community, Haskell makes it easier to produce flexible, maintainable, high-quality software.
&amp;ndash; Haskell.</description></item><item><title>Distributed Version Control Systems</title><link>/events/2012-01-05-distributed-version-control-systems/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2012-01-05-distributed-version-control-systems/</guid><description>January 5th, 2012 at 7:00PM in Dreese 266, Paul Schwendenman, Meisam Fathi Salmi and Daniel Thau will be giving presentations on Distributed Version Control Systems (DVCS). DVCSs are distributed systems which keep track of software revisions. These are usually, but not necessarily, used to manage programming projects. Daniel will go over the idea behind a DVCS, as well as some of the stuff going on under the hood in one of them (git).</description></item><item><title>Open Source Operating Systems and Winter 2011 Planning</title><link>/events/2011-12-01-open-source-operating-systems-and-winter-2011-planning/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2011-12-01-open-source-operating-systems-and-winter-2011-planning/</guid><description>Thursday, December 1st at 7:00PM in Dreese room 266, a number of our members will be presenting on various Open Source Operating Systems. These will not be overly in-depth as some of our past presentations have been; rather, these should just taste of what these Operating Systems are like or why people may be interested in learning more about them.
Additionally, we will plan out the topics for our meetings quarter.</description></item><item><title>LAN Party</title><link>/events/2011-11-19-lan-party/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2011-11-19-lan-party/</guid><description>Saturday, November 19th from 10:30AM-11:30PM (yes, 13 hours!) in the Ohio Union Interfaith Prayer and Reflection, the Open Source Club will be hosting a LAN party!
We will be focusing on open source gaming, but those with proprietary games on proprietary platforms will be welcome as well. For more information, see http://opensource.osu.edu/lan
Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to bring your own computer, ethernet cable and surge protector.
Hope to see you there!</description></item><item><title>Open Source Multiplayer Games</title><link>/events/2011-11-17-open-source-multiplayer-games/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2011-11-17-open-source-multiplayer-games/</guid><description>This week I will be demonstrating several open source multiplayer games we will be playing at our LAN party on Saturday!
I will be doing live demonstrations on live severs we will use for the event, so feel free to install the games on your laptop and join me in-game.
Here is a short list of the games we will be playing. This list will likely change up until the LAN party.</description></item><item><title>Clojure</title><link>/events/2011-11-10-clojure/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2011-11-10-clojure/</guid><description>November 10th at 7:00PM in Dreese 266, Maxim Kim will be giving a presentation on Clojure. Clojure is a dynamic programming language that targets the Java Virtual Machine (and the CLR, and JavaScript). It is designed to be a general-purpose language, combining the approachability and interactive development of a scripting language with an efficient and robust infrastructure for multithreaded programming. Clojure is a compiled language - it compiles directly to JVM bytecode, yet remains completely dynamic.</description></item><item><title>This Week in Slashdot</title><link>/events/2011-11-03-this-week-in-slashdot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2011-11-03-this-week-in-slashdot/</guid><description>This Thursday, in Dreese Labs room 266, Alex Lingo will host his infamous _This Week in Slashdot_™ discussion. As is the general format, Alex will display and discuss major events in technology, with feedback from the audience. For the uninitiated, Slashdot (often abbreviated /.) is a nerd-oriented news website where the readers submit articles which are then accepted or rejected by editors and then published on the front page, with a new page typically appearing every couple of hours.</description></item><item><title>Regular Expressions</title><link>/events/2011-10-27-regular-expressions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2011-10-27-regular-expressions/</guid><description>October 27th at 7:00PM in Dreese 266, Daniel Thau will be giving a presentation on Regular Expressions. Regular Expressions is a system for pattern recognition in text which is extremely useful for text processing. This talk may be especially appealing to up-and-coming *nix admins, since such systems rely heavily on text for things like configuration, but should be useful for anyone interested in software. The talk will mostly use examples with the grep and sed utilities, which are almost certainly already installed on your Linux or OSX laptops if you&amp;rsquo;re bringing one along.</description></item><item><title>Xiki</title><link>/events/2011-10-20-xiki/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2011-10-20-xiki/</guid><description>October 20th at 7:00PM in Dreese 266, Paul Schwendenman will be giving a presentation on Xiki. Xiki is a modified version of emacs created specifically for web development with the goal of having an easy learning curve. Additionally, there will be a discussion and vote regarding some changes to the club constitution. Link to slides</description></item><item><title>Vim</title><link>/events/2011-10-10-vim/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2011-10-10-vim/</guid><description>October 13th at 7:00PM in Dreese 266, Daniel Thau will be giving a presentation on Vim, an extremely powerful text editing program. Vim is known for having a difficult learning curve, but for many of those who do any appreciable amount of work editing text (such as Unix configuration, programming, etc) the benefits can far outweigh the cost. Daniel will cover Vim&amp;rsquo;s basic concepts and should get most who know nothing about Vim up to the point where they can use it.</description></item><item><title>Making Pictures Lie</title><link>/events/2011-10-03-making-pictures-lie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2011-10-03-making-pictures-lie/</guid><description>This Thursday, in Dreese Lab room 266, I will demonstrating how you can make pictures lie using only open source software. Fanboys will often proclaim what they can do in a certain expensive proprietary image editor that shall not be named, so I&amp;rsquo;m going to demonstrate just the same things are do-able from another certain free, open source program. My claim is that GIMP is just as capable of making your pictures lie as any other mainstream image manipulation software.</description></item><item><title>Wireless Hacking</title><link>/events/2011-09-29-wireless-hacking/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2011-09-29-wireless-hacking/</guid><description>Thursday, September 29th at 7:00PM in Dreese Labs 266, Michael Yanovich will be covering wireless security with a heavy regard towards wireless hacking. He will be covering how wireless networks work, the several types of encryption available, and other settings that can set to try to protect your network. He will be demonstrating these attacks as well, and he encourages people to bring their laptops if they wish to participate (if your wireless card can not run the available software, he will be providing a sample dump for you to play around with, this will be available at the meeting).</description></item><item><title>First meeting</title><link>/events/2011-09-22-first-meeting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2011-09-22-first-meeting/</guid><description>Thursday, September 22nd at 7:00PM in Dreese Labs room 266, the Ohio State University Open Source Club will have its first meeting of the 2011-2012 academic year. Daniel Thau will be giving an introduction to the concept of Free/Open Source Software to help explain to any [potential] new members what the club is about. After that we&amp;rsquo;ll have a PGP signing party (we&amp;rsquo;ll likely have a talk on what PGP is some time next quarter).</description></item><item><title>Web Application Security</title><link>/events/2011-06-02-web-application-security/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2011-06-02-web-application-security/</guid><description>This Thursday, June 2nd at 7PM in Dreese Labs 264, Jonathan Tubb and Brian Swaney will be presenting on compromising and exploiting web systems and will focus on some of the techniques as well as actual examples. The talk itself will be shorter than a normal meeting so that planning meetings for next year and organizing summer events can take place.
As always the OSU Open Source Club does not condone illegal activities and is not responsible for any misuse of the techniques learned in this meeting.</description></item><item><title>Arduino</title><link>/events/2011-05-26-arduino/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2011-05-26-arduino/</guid><description>This Thursday, May 26 at 7PM, we will be meeting in Hitchcock 224 where First Year Engineering staff will present on Arduino.
Come to a hands-on open hardware/open source Arduino microcontroller introduction given by the staff of First Year Engineering (FYE) program with an emphasis on their new lab centered about the &amp;ldquo;Advance Energy Vehicle (AEV),&amp;rdquo; controlled, of course, by an Arduino. FYE will supply computer accounts and breadboards with installed Arduinos, so you can cruise through some simple hands-on examples of controlling motors, servos, acquiring analog data, reading and writing to digital pins, and effectively using interrupts (simpler than you would imagine) with this simple eight bit device.</description></item><item><title>Functional Programming</title><link>/events/2011-05-19-functional-programming/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2011-05-19-functional-programming/</guid><description>Have you ever wondered what functional programming is all about or how to use funky languages people are always talking about? This Thursday, May 19 at 7PM in Dreese 264, Alex Burkhart will describe the basic concept of functional programming and introduce us to Haskell. Next, Silas Baronda will present Erlang.</description></item><item><title>LAN Party</title><link>/events/2011-05-14-lan-party/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2011-05-14-lan-party/</guid><description>On Saturday, May 14, from 10:00AM to 11:30PM in the Ohio Union Creative Arts room. The emphasis will be on Free, Open Source games, but people are welcome to play whatever they&amp;rsquo;d like. Additional details can be found at the LAN website as well as a registration form, to help us get a feel for how many people we will have and what games you want to play. Please bring your computer, any game media you might need, as well as a network cable or two, in case some people do not have one.</description></item><item><title>Elections</title><link>/events/2011-05-12-elections/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2011-05-12-elections/</guid><description>Club elections will be held May 12, 2011. If you are interested in running, please email elections@opensource.osu.edu in order to be listed here and in the meeting announcement. Any OSU student who has been to at least one meeting is eligible to run for president, vice president, or treasurer.
The following people have announced their candidacy.
President: Daniel Thau Vice President: Paul Schwendenman, Brian Swaney (tentative) Treasurer: Joel Friedly
In addition, Brian Swaney has proposed the following ballot initiative.</description></item><item><title>Mandatory Access Control</title><link>/events/2011-05-05-mandatory-access-control/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2011-05-05-mandatory-access-control/</guid><description>This Thursday, May 5th at 7PM in Dreese Labs 264, Daniel Thau and Alek Rollyson will be presenting on Linux Mandatory Access Control (MAC). MAC is a different approach to computer security from the Discretionary Access Control (DAC) that is the default for Windows, Macs, most Linux distros, and most other Unixy operating systems. The basic concepts behind MAC will be explained, contrasted against DAC, and various options for MAC on Linux will be covered (with specific focus given to SELinux and TOMOYO Linux).</description></item><item><title>CLI Utilities</title><link>/events/2011-04-28-cli-utilities/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2011-04-28-cli-utilities/</guid><description>On Thursday, April 28, at 7PM in Dreese 264, we will have lightning talks about programs with a command-line interface (CLI). These utilities can be useful in their own right, but often can be connected together with pipes to do new and interesting things. It would be helpful if people interested in presenting signed up with their choices, either by emailing me at meinwald.1@osu.edu or commenting below. This way we can avoid duplication.</description></item><item><title>Breaking Stuff</title><link>/events/2011-04-21-breaking-stuff/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2011-04-21-breaking-stuff/</guid><description>Have you ever run &amp;ldquo;rm -rf&amp;rdquo; on the wrong directory, ran &amp;ldquo;rsync&amp;rdquo; the wrong way, observed unintended consequences with &amp;ldquo;find,&amp;rdquo; or locked yourself out of your own computer? If you can answer yes to any of these and would like to know what else to avoid, or if you can&amp;rsquo;t and would like to keep it that way, please join us as various club members present how to break things! Everyone who has a story or a deadly command, please come and share it with us, no prior approval needed.</description></item><item><title>Quiz Bowl</title><link>/events/2011-04-20-quiz-bowl/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2011-04-20-quiz-bowl/</guid><description>UPE and ACM-W have once again invited us to a quiz bowl competition. On Wednesday, April 20, at 6:30 PM in Lazenby 021, teams of students and faculty will be competing to answer computer science-related questions, perhaps with a few other topics occasionally mixed in. This time, people will be choosing their own teams. You can sign up your team in the CSE advising office on the third floor of Dreese.</description></item><item><title>Go (board game) AI</title><link>/events/2011-04-14-go-board-game-ai/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2011-04-14-go-board-game-ai/</guid><description>This Thursday, April 14th at 7PM in Dreese 264, Daniel Thau will be giving a presentation on open source artificial intelligence for the board game Go.
Go is an ancient board game (estimated to be 2000-4000 years old) which, despite a simple rule set, is extremely difficult to write a human-level AI for. Unlike comparable board games such as Chess, the best Go AI&amp;rsquo;s in the world were not match against strong club players only a few years ago, and despite significant development recently they are still no match for weaker professional Go players today.</description></item><item><title/><link>/events/2011-04-07-open-source-security-tools/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2011-04-07-open-source-security-tools/</guid><description>This Thursday, April 7 at 7PM in Dreese 264, Alek Rollyson will be covering open source security tools from protocol analyzers to vulnerability scanners. This talk is meant as a general overview of tools available as well as their practical applications in security audits and penetration testing. Tools and topics covered will include:
Wireshark (protocol analyzer) Metasploit (penetration testing suite) Ettercap (multipurpose sniffer/interceptor/logger for switched LAN) Aircrack-ng (set of tools for testing wireless security) OpenVAS (open source replacement for Nessus, a vulnerability scanner) Nmap (swiss army port scanner) Password Crackers (John the Ripper, Ophcrack) Distros such as Backtrack, Knoppix STD, Damn Vulnerable Linux Kippo (simple honeypot with recording capabilities) A few hardening techniques and tools (mandatory access control, port knocking, intrusion detection tools, common sense things, old wive&amp;rsquo;s tales) NOTE: This talk is meant for educational purposes only.</description></item><item><title>New Microsoft Partnership</title><link>/events/2011-04-01-new-microsoft-partnership/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2011-04-01-new-microsoft-partnership/</guid><description>Amidst our past rivalry, and a fellow technology group that has been all but extinct, we in the Ohio State University Open Source Club have hereby formed a new partnership with the now re-established ntSig (website coming soon). ntSig, or New Technology Special Interest Group, is a group sponsored by Microsoft for people who share an interest in software, computers and technology in general. This carefully considered decision was not made lightly, but we wish to honor some of our former members who now reside in Redmond, WA and set our political differences aside.</description></item><item><title>Window Managers and Desktop Environments</title><link>/events/2011-03-31-window-managers-and-desktop-environments/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2011-03-31-window-managers-and-desktop-environments/</guid><description>This Thursday, March 31 at 7PM in Dreese 264 we will see presentations on window managers and desktop environments. Dan Thau will show the window managers dwm and Openbox as well as LXDE which uses the latter. Mike Yanovich will demonstrate the Awesome window manager and Gnome desktop environment (version 2.x). Alek Rollyson will present Window Manager From Scratch. Alex Lingo will talk about KDE. Mike Bettencourt will introduce Gnome 3.</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>/events/2011-03-10-projects/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2011-03-10-projects/</guid><description>This Thursday, March 10 at 7PM in Dreese 264, we will be having lightning talks on the Open Source projects people are working on. If you have something you are working on, please comment below so I can get an idea of the time limits for these talks. If you don&amp;rsquo;t hear otherwise, assume they are five minutes each and a maximum of two talks per person. If anyone has a gong to help enforce these guidelines, please let me know.</description></item><item><title>Shells</title><link>/events/2011-03-03-shells/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2011-03-03-shells/</guid><description>On Thursday, March 3, at 7PM in Dreese 264, we will be having talks on shells. Dan Thau will explain ZSH, an extremely customizable and powerfull shell. Morgan Goose will present on Bash, a familiar one that still has some tricks up its sleeve. Michael Yanovich will demonstrate either ipython or bpython, a python-based shell. Matt Meinwald will show Fish, a friendlier shell. If anyone else has a shell to present, please feel free to talk for a few minutes on it.</description></item><item><title>Android Development</title><link>/events/2011-02-24-android-development/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2011-02-24-android-development/</guid><description>On Thursday, February 24, at 7PM in Dreese 264, Sogeti USA developers Jackie Gleason and Robert Omalley will discuss Android for beginning to intermediate Java developers.
After an introduction to Sogeti and possible careers, the beginning of the presentation is a &amp;ldquo;What is Android?&amp;rdquo; section where Jackie and Robert will talk about the history of android, what the current environment is like, and what to look forward to in the future.</description></item><item><title>Markup Languages</title><link>/events/2011-02-17-markup-languages/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2011-02-17-markup-languages/</guid><description>This Thursday, in Dreese Lab room 264, several of our members will be giving presentations on various markup languages.
Matt Meinwald will be going over XML. Alex Lingo will present HTML. Paul Schwendenman will be educating us on HAML. Silas Baronda will be covering reStructuredText. Daniel Thau will be presenting LaTeX. Finally, Alek Rollyson will be covering Markdown.
If you feel you can cover a markup language that isn&amp;rsquo;t already covered, even briefly, feel free to make a post and we&amp;rsquo;ll see if we can add you.</description></item><item><title>Wireless Hacking</title><link>/events/2011-02-10-wireless-hacking/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2011-02-10-wireless-hacking/</guid><description>Tonight at 7 pm in Dreese Labs room 264, I, Michael Yanovich, will be covering various sub-topics to wireless hacking, however the main point that I want people to take away from this talk is how to secure your own wireless network from these types of attacks. I&amp;rsquo;ll be covering a brief outline on how wireless networks work, the several types of encryption available, and other settings that can set to try to protect your network.</description></item><item><title>Microcontrollers</title><link>/events/2011-02-03-microcontrollers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2011-02-03-microcontrollers/</guid><description>This Thursday, February 3 at 7PM in Dreese 264, Jonathan Tubb will be going over the basics of Microcontrollers, uses, and programming. Specific devices will include the TI MSP line of chips as well as Arduino (Atmega). Finished projects will also be brought in as examples. Feel free to bring and show off your own projects.
As always there will be pizza.</description></item><item><title>An Introduction to Blender!</title><link>/events/2011-01-27-an-introduction-to-blender/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2011-01-27-an-introduction-to-blender/</guid><description>This Thursday, Alex Lingo will be presenting on the topic of Blender. Blender is a powerful 3D modeling and rendering program, similar to applications such as Maya or 3DS Max. Alex&amp;rsquo;s presentation will cover the history of blender, basic 3D modeling concepts, how to control Blender with the keyboard and mouse, and will conclude with a live demonstration that will hopefully go as planned, with no mistakes or confusion, guaranteed.</description></item><item><title>Quiz Bowl with UPE and ACM-W</title><link>/events/2011-01-20-quiz-bowl-with-upe-and-acm-w/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2011-01-20-quiz-bowl-with-upe-and-acm-w/</guid><description>This Thursday, January 20, in Dreese Labs room 480 at 7PM, we will be participating in a quiz bowl event with UPE and ACM-W. This event will consist of a qualifier round where two teams of four will be selected based on individual knowledge of computer science trivia. These teams will face each other, then the winning team will face a faculty team. There will be pizza, pop, and prizes.</description></item><item><title>Gimp Image Editing - Winter 2011</title><link>/events/2011-01-13-gimp-image-editing-winter-2011/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2011-01-13-gimp-image-editing-winter-2011/</guid><description>This Thursday, at 7 pm in Dreese Labs room 264, Brian Swaney will be demonstrating use of the GIMP image editor. GIMP is what some might consider an open source alternative to the proprietary $800 Photoshop application, except that many people refuse to consider it on the grounds that it is allegedly inferior, and therefore unusable. While I&amp;rsquo;m not familiar with Photoshop, I will debunk the myth about GIMP being unusable, and show just how powerful GIMP can be for those who take the time to learn it.</description></item><item><title>Chroot and Linux from Scratch</title><link>/events/2011-01-06-chroot-and-linux-from-scatch/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2011-01-06-chroot-and-linux-from-scatch/</guid><description>Thursday, January 6th, 2011 at 7:00PM in Dreese 264 (note the change in location), Daniel Thau will be giving a dual presentation covering the chroot operation as well as the Linux From Scratch project.
Chroot, available on all major Unix-y systems, changes the root directory from the point of a selected program and its children. Effectively, this is somewhat akin to vitalization (with a number of comparative benefits and deficiencies relative to actual vitalization).</description></item><item><title>OSU Sign-on and OpenID Now Supported</title><link>/events/2011-01-04-osu-sign-on-and-openid-now-supported/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2011-01-04-osu-sign-on-and-openid-now-supported/</guid><description>In response to feedback we received about having to log into our site (and resetting passwords each time), as well as insanely difficult CAPTCHAs, we have taken steps to make things a little easier for everyone. Effective immediately, an OSU name.n will now log any current student, faculty, or staff member into our website, as well as most alumni and former staff. To use it, simply click the link on the left-side of any page titled &amp;ldquo;OSU Sign-on&amp;rdquo; and enter your OSU username and password (same password you use for Carmen/grades/etc).</description></item><item><title>Finals and Winter Break</title><link>/events/2010-12-05-finals-and-winter-break/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2010-12-05-finals-and-winter-break/</guid><description>The week of December 3 is final exams, so we will not be meeting. In addition, the next few weeks are winter break, so our next meeting is Thursday, January 10 at 7 PM. The topic and location are currently unknown. During this break, our irc channel and mailing list should still be active and many will be working on projects, some of which are hosted on our website. Hopefully everyone has an enjoyable break, and we&amp;rsquo;ll see you next quarter.</description></item><item><title>Vim</title><link>/events/2010-12-02-vim/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2010-12-02-vim/</guid><description>December 2nd at 7:00PM in the Ohio Union Senate Chamber Daniel Thau will be giving a presentation on Vim, an extremely powerful text editing program. Vim is known for having a difficult learning curve, but for many of those who do any appreciable amount of work editing text (such as Unix configuration, programming, etc) the benefits can far outweigh the cost.
Daniel will cover Vim&amp;rsquo;s basic concepts and should get most who know nothing about Vim up to the point where they can use it.</description></item><item><title>No Meeting this Week</title><link>/events/2010-11-21-no-meeting-this-week/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2010-11-21-no-meeting-this-week/</guid><description>Due to the Thanksgiving holiday on Thursday, we will not have a meeting this week. The next meeting is December 2, and will be about Vim and planning for next quarter.</description></item><item><title>Xen Virtualization</title><link>/events/2010-11-18-xen-virtualization/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2010-11-18-xen-virtualization/</guid><description>On Thursday, November 18, at 7:00PM in the Ohio Union Senate Chamber, Matt Meinwald will be presenting on Xen, a popular server virtualization system. He will show what the software has to offer and will demo the installation process on Debian. Depending on time and interest, he may explain how we use it in the Open Source club systems or compare it to other software out there.</description></item><item><title>The Git Distributed Version Control System</title><link>/events/2010-11-12-the-git-distributed-version-control-system/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2010-11-12-the-git-distributed-version-control-system/</guid><description>This Friday, November 12th at 7:00PM in the Ohio Union Senate Chamber Daniel Thau will be giving a presentation on Git, a distributed version control system with a focus on performance and integrity. Despite being known as one of the more difficult VCSs to grasp, git has become quite popular and has a fair number of recognizable F/OSS projects using it, such as the Linux Kernel and X.org. Daniel will cover a quick history of Git (lots of tasty drama), cover some pros and cons of using Git, explain what Git is doing under the hood, give a conceptual explanation of what Git does, and of course go over both basic (add, commit, branch, merge, etc) and advanced (stash, rebase, etc) Git usage.</description></item><item><title>Model View Controllers</title><link>/events/2010-11-04-model-view-controllers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2010-11-04-model-view-controllers/</guid><description>This Thursday, November 4th at 7PM in the Ohio Union Senate Chamber, Jonathan Tubb will be giving an overview of Model View Controllers. A popular architecture for developing web applications, MVCs have come into their own in the past decade becoming the standard for quick deployment of applications. Information, use cases, and examples of MVCs and web applications will be covered.
Also featuring Tubbs witty remarks and dashing good looks, maybe even pizza.</description></item><item><title>This Week in Slashdot</title><link>/events/2010-10-28-this-week-in-slashdot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2010-10-28-this-week-in-slashdot/</guid><description>This Thursday, October 28 at 7PM in the Ohio Union Senate Chamber, Alex Lingo will be presenting an old club favorite known as &amp;ldquo;This Week in Slashdot&amp;rdquo;. Slashdot (commonly abbreviated as /.) is a website that deals in news for the nerdy, specifically &amp;ldquo;stuff that matters&amp;rdquo;. Readers submit articles which are then accepted or rejected by editors and published on the site. From there, the readers have huge discussions about every aspect of the article which can be very funny/interesting/insightful/etc and oft prove to be a very good read.</description></item><item><title>Why Python?</title><link>/events/2010-10-21-why-python/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2010-10-21-why-python/</guid><description>This meeting will focus on several aspects of Python that don&amp;rsquo;t normally come up in normal Python meetings. It will show you how things can be easier and more fun in Python! I will will be covering things from as simply as handling basic data types to more advance things such as making system calls or making the most of the PSL (Python Standard Library).
This meeting will also attempt to cover a small comparison between the larger more known languages: Java and C++, and show how some things can be done easier and quicker than in Java or C++.</description></item><item><title>GIMP Image editing - Autumn 2010</title><link>/events/2010-10-14-gimp-image-editing-autumn-2010/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2010-10-14-gimp-image-editing-autumn-2010/</guid><description>This Thursday, at 7 pm in the Ohio Union Senate Chamber, Brian Swaney will be demonstrating use of the GIMP image editor. GIMP is what some might consider an open source alternative to the proprietary $800 Photoshop application, except that many people refuse to consider it on the grounds that it is allegedly inferior, and therefore unusable. While I&amp;rsquo;m not familiar with Photoshop, I will debunk the myth about GIMP being unusable, and show just how powerful GIMP can be for those who take the time to learn it.</description></item><item><title>Mua the Mutt</title><link>/events/2010-10-07-mua-the-mutt/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2010-10-07-mua-the-mutt/</guid><description>On Thursday, October 7th at 7PM in the Ohio Union Senate Chamber, Alek Rollyson will be explaining what Mutt is, what it does, and why you should care. Per Mutt&amp;rsquo;s mantra, most e-mail clients suck, Mutt just sucks less. Alek will be showcasing Mutt&amp;rsquo;s capabilities via the story of Mua the Mutt and the adventures in which she partakes. Through a storytelling device, he will explain that Mutt is solely a mail user agent and requires other pieces and parts in order to function as a complete email solution.</description></item><item><title>Blood Drive</title><link>/events/2010-09-30-blood-drive/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2010-09-30-blood-drive/</guid><description>This Thursday, September 30 from 12-6PM, we are sponsoring a Red Cross blood drive in Dreese Lab. If you would like to schedule a time to donate blood between 12PM and 6PM, you would like to help at the table between 11AM and 7PM, or if you have any questions, please contact Matt Meinwald (meinwald.1@osu.edu).</description></item><item><title>Open Source Music Ripper / Server / Client</title><link>/events/2010-09-30-open-source-music-ripper-server-client/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2010-09-30-open-source-music-ripper-server-client/</guid><description>This Thursday, at 7 pm in the Ohio Union Senate Chamber, Matt Smith will be demonstrating an Open Music Server that he has been working on. It might seem too easy and obvious to bother with in this day and age. We all know how to rip CD&amp;rsquo;s, collect and share music, and move it to our portables for on-the-go music. My server comes from an audiophile standpoint. Long story short, I used to sell expensive stereo equipment.</description></item><item><title>Overview of free desktop operating systems</title><link>/events/2010-09-23-overview-of-free-desktop-operating-systems/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2010-09-23-overview-of-free-desktop-operating-systems/</guid><description>Thursday, September 23 is the first meeting of autumn quarter. We will be meeting in the Ohio Union Senate Room (note the change in location from last year) at 7PM. After a short introduction of the club and a brief description of the blood drive we are sponsoring on the 30th, Matt Meinwald will present an overview of Free operating systems, focusing primarily on GNU/Linux distributions. The main software component of a computer is its operating system, and it is good to know we have plenty of Free and Open Source options for this important role.</description></item><item><title>Ohio Linuxfest September 10-12</title><link>/events/2010-09-10-ohio-linuxfest-september-10-12/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2010-09-10-ohio-linuxfest-september-10-12/</guid><description>Ohio Linuxfest starts this Friday, September 10 at the Greater Columbus Convention Center. Various events occur that day, but the main part of the conference is Saturday, which consists of talks from 9am to 7:30pm and an expo with many Linux-related organizations. The Open Source club has a table at the expo, so please stop by.</description></item><item><title>Planning Meeting [8/17/2010]</title><link>/events/2010-08-17-planning-meeting/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2010-08-17-planning-meeting/</guid><description>We will be having a planning meeting at 7:30PM on Tuesday, August 17, in Dreese Labs room 266.
This meeting will mostly be aimed at preparing for autumn quarter, including scheduling as many of those meetings as possible, and deciding on our fall event. If time permits, it will also include a technical overview of our computer systems for future admins. This meeting is optional, but strongly encouraged for officers, and somewhat encouraged for people interested in presenting next quarter.</description></item><item><title>PyOhio</title><link>/events/2010-07-31-pyohio/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2010-07-31-pyohio/</guid><description>This weekend, July 31 and August 1, will be PyOhio! PyOhio is a yearly conference about Python that takes place here in Columbus, Ohio at The Ohio State University (in The Union located at 1739 N. High St.) It&amp;rsquo;s a FREE event to learn almost anything about Python. There are several talks discussing many different about Python or relating to Python in many different ways. The list of specific topics can be found here: http://www.</description></item><item><title>Unofficial Meeting 6/24</title><link>/events/2010-06-24-unofficial-meeting-6-24/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2010-06-24-unofficial-meeting-6-24/</guid><description>On Thursday, June 24 at 7:00 PM, in Dreese 305, there is an unofficial meeting, hosted by Alex Lingo. The main topic is planning these kinds of meetings for the rest of the summer, but there should be plenty of interesting discussion.</description></item><item><title>YAPC</title><link>/events/2010-06-21-yapc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2010-06-21-yapc/</guid><description>Yet Another Perl Conference: North America, YAPC::NA for short, is occurring from June 21 to June 23, in the new Ohio Union. Ohio State students can get in for free if they follow these instructions: http://yapc2010.com/yn2010/osustudents.html. If we already know you, send an email to yapc@opensource.osu.edu and we can vouch for you. Note this is not an email for general inquiries about the conference - for that, use organizers@yapc2010.com. For non-students, the price is $100 for all the events Monday through Wednesday, or $30-$40 for individual days, which is really quite reasonable for a conference of this size.</description></item><item><title>Perl</title><link>/events/2010-06-03-perl/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2010-06-03-perl/</guid><description>This Thursday, June 3rd at 7PM in Dreese Labs 305, Robert Joseph will be presenting on the scripting language Perl. This timing fits nicely because the Open Source Club is hosting Yet Another Perl Conference::North America 2010 later this month and we felt it was appropriate that we should prepare ourselves. More info will be posted soon.</description></item><item><title>Elections for the 2010/2011 Year</title><link>/events/2010-05-27-elections-for-the-2010-2011-year/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2010-05-27-elections-for-the-2010-2011-year/</guid><description>On Thursday, May 27th at 7PM (before our regularly scheduled meeting) in Dreese Labs 305, we will be holding officer elections for the coming 2010/2011 year. If you are interested in running for a position, send an email to elections@opensource.osu.edu with your full name, year, major and a short description of yourself and/or running platform. The elections will last a half hour and the regular meeting will begin at 7:30 PM.</description></item><item><title>Game Tournament</title><link>/events/2010-05-22-game-tournament/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2010-05-22-game-tournament/</guid><description>On Saturday, May 22 in the Ohio Union, the Ohio State Open Source Club will be hosting a LAN Party from 10 AM Saturday morning until 3 AM Sunday morning. Per our Free and open source philosophy, we will be promoting games that either run natively in Linux or run well in WINE and, while some of the games themselves might not be free or open source in nature, we would like to show how gaming in Linux is not a lost cause.</description></item><item><title>Open Source Gaming</title><link>/events/2010-05-20-open-source-gaming/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2010-05-20-open-source-gaming/</guid><description>This Thursday, May 20th at 7PM in Dreese Labs 305, we will be discussing open source gaming, gaming on Linux, gaming with WINE, and just general options for gaming once you switch to an open source operating system. One complaint that seems common in the open source OS world is that gaming is pretty much thrown out the window once you have made the switch. We would like to spend the meeting debunking this myth and showing all of the options that one has in the open source gaming arena.</description></item><item><title>This Week In Slashdot</title><link>/events/2010-05-06-this-week-in-slashdot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2010-05-06-this-week-in-slashdot/</guid><description>This Thursday, May 6th at 7PM in Caldwell 133 (note the change), Alex Lingo will be presenting an old club favorite known as &amp;ldquo;This Week in Slashdot&amp;rdquo;. Slashdot (commonly abbreviated as /.) is a website located at http://slashdot.org that deals in news for the nerdy. Readers submit articles which are then accepted or rejected by editors and then published on the site. From there, the readers have huge discussions about every aspect of the article which can be very funny/interesting/insightful/etc and oft prove to be a very good read.</description></item><item><title>(Attempting) Linux on Anything</title><link>/events/2010-04-29-attempting-linux-on-anything/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2010-04-29-attempting-linux-on-anything/</guid><description>This Thursday, April 29th at 7PM in Dreese Labs 317, we will be spending the meeting time attempting to install Linux on anything. We have members with PS3&amp;rsquo;s, iPods, XBOX&amp;rsquo;s, Wii&amp;rsquo;s, phones and whatever else you can think of and we are going to attempt to install an operating system of our choice on them. These members are volunteering their hardware for the meeting and recognize that performing these actions may violate warranties and are not responsible for attempts made meeting goers' own electronics.</description></item><item><title>ShellCoding</title><link>/events/2010-04-27-shellcoding/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2010-04-27-shellcoding/</guid><description>This Thursday, May 27th at 7:30PM in Dreese Labs 305, Jon Tubb will be talking about ShellCoding and other subversion methods. Delve into the magical world of assembly as we explore the inner workings of your favorite software and then make it do your bidding. Botnets, wireless hacking, and everything else you need to get started will be presented. **This meeting is provided for informational purposes only and using these techniques on equipment that is not owned by the tester is not condoned by the Open Source Club.</description></item><item><title>Mandatory Access Control</title><link>/events/2010-04-18-mandatory-access-control/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2010-04-18-mandatory-access-control/</guid><description>This Thursday, May 13th at 7PM in Dreese Labs 305, Daniel Thau will be presenting on Linux Mandatory Access Control (MAC). MAC is a different approach to computer security from the Discretionary Access Control (DAC) that is the default for Windows, Macs, most Linux distros, and most other Unixy operating systems. The basic concepts behind MAC will be explained, contrasted against DAC, and various options for MAC on Linux will be covered (with specific focus given to SELinux and TOMOYO Linux).</description></item><item><title>Open Source GIS</title><link>/events/2010-04-18-open-source-gis/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2010-04-18-open-source-gis/</guid><description>This Thursday, April 22nd at 7PM in Dreese Labs 305, Jesse Amundsen, a student in the Physics and Geology department at Northern Kentucky University, will discuss the current state of open source geographic information systems (GIS). This will include a brief introduction to the components, functions, and uses of a GIS followed by an exploration of current open source offerings and how they compare to the current proprietary powerhouse that is ESRI&amp;rsquo;s ArcGIS.</description></item><item><title>Nifty Tips and Tricks</title><link>/events/2010-04-15-nifty-tips-and-tricks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2010-04-15-nifty-tips-and-tricks/</guid><description>This Thursday, April 15th at 7PM in Dreese Labs 305, we will be hosting a discussion session revolving around tips, tricks, and time savers that people have discovered. Do you think you have an awesome .bashrc, .vimrc, key binding, or a little known useful program and want to show it off? This would be the perfect opportunity to share with the rest of the club. There are lots of nifty things that are not widely known and we think this would be a good opportunity to share your knowledge of time savers with others!</description></item><item><title>Language Lightning Talks</title><link>/events/2010-04-08-language-lightning-talks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2010-04-08-language-lightning-talks/</guid><description>This Thursday, April 8th at 7PM in Dreese Labs 305, we will be holding a lightning talk session focusing on programming languages. It came to our attention that knowledge of different languages was fragmented amongst meeting goers so we decided that we should each take turns introducing each other to languages that we have learned and think others would appreciate or find useful. The lightning talk format consists of short talks that each focus on a single topic and are typically given by multiple presenters in succession.</description></item><item><title>GIMP - Spring 2010</title><link>/events/2010-04-01-gimp-spring-2010/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2010-04-01-gimp-spring-2010/</guid><description>Notice: Due to inexcusably poor service from classroom services, the meeting was moved to Dreese Lab 305 for the current meeting. We apologize for the short notice, and plan on inquiring into why our room was overbooked without our knowledge.
Thursday, April 1st, at 7PM in Dreese Labs 266, Brian Swaney demonstrated how to effectively utilize the open source photo editing suite GIMP.
Image manipulation is done a by-case basis, so what works on one image may not work on another.</description></item><item><title>Command Line Applications</title><link>/events/2010-03-11-command-line-applications/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2010-03-11-command-line-applications/</guid><description>This Thursday, March 11th at 7PM in Dreese Labs 266, we will be holding a lightning talk session covering a multitude of command line applications. The lightning talk format consists of short talks that focus on a single topic and are typically given by multiple presenters in succession. If you are looking for a lightweight program to get the job done and don&amp;rsquo;t need a graphical interface, be it checking your mail, downloading torrents, chatting on irc, editing text, or anything else, this is definitely the meeting for you.</description></item><item><title>Maximizing Battery Life in Linux</title><link>/events/2010-03-04-maximizing-battery-life-in-linux/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2010-03-04-maximizing-battery-life-in-linux/</guid><description>Thursday March 4th, at 7PM in Dreese Labs room 266, Dan Thau will be showing us how to maximize your laptop&amp;rsquo;s battery life in Linux. You may be wondering once you made the switch from Windows or Mac why your laptop hasn&amp;rsquo;t been lasting as long without power. Dan will be showing common battery stretching techniques as well as some extreme measures you can take in order to get the most out of your laptop battery.</description></item><item><title>Mini Hackathon!</title><link>/events/2010-02-18-mini-hackathon/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2010-02-18-mini-hackathon/</guid><description>Due to mitigating circumstances we will not be having our maximizing battery talk this week. In lieu of this we will be holding a hackathon in its stead. This Thursday, February 18th at 7PM in Dreese Labs 266, we will be hacking on all sorts of code. We have several projects going at the moment that range from python to C and hackers of all skill levels are invited. Whether you know nothing about programming or are a kernel wizard come join us and play around with some code.</description></item><item><title>Alternative Window Managers</title><link>/events/2010-02-11-alternative-window-managers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2010-02-11-alternative-window-managers/</guid><description>Thursday February 11th, at 7PM in Dreese Labs 266, we will be discussing alternative open source window managers for Linux. A window manager is system software that controls the placement and appearance of windows within a windowing system in a graphical user interface. In other words it creates a desktop environment for you to use on your screen. The big two desktop environments are KDE and Gnome, but we are going to discuss some lesser known alternatives to these two.</description></item><item><title>Intermediate and Advanced Python</title><link>/events/2010-02-04-intermediate-and-advanced-python/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2010-02-04-intermediate-and-advanced-python/</guid><description>Thursday February 4th, at 7PM in Dreese Labs 266, Michael Yanovich and Morgan Goose will be demonstrating some intermediate and advanced uses of Python. They have several tips and tricks to demonstrate, so come out and learn more about the Python language! Morgan&amp;rsquo;s slides are available and notes are attached.</description></item><item><title>GNU Utilities</title><link>/events/2010-01-28-gnu-utilities/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2010-01-28-gnu-utilities/</guid><description>This Thursday January 28th, at 7PM in Dreese Labs 266, Morgan Goose will be showing off a multitude of GNU Utilties. Here is Morgan&amp;rsquo;s synopsis of his talk:
This presentation is going to try and cover a lot of ground, and at variable speed. I am trying to get it into two somewhat logical parts.
First being where I into regex then show its use with sed. Then go into using awk, and finally how to use find.</description></item><item><title>Virtualization</title><link>/events/2010-01-21-virtualization/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2010-01-21-virtualization/</guid><description>This Thursday, January 21st at 7PM in Dreese Labs 266, we will have a few people presenting on the topic of virtualization. Dan Thau will be talking about chroot, what chroot is and what chroot is not, as well as give examples for usage and a demo or two. Matt Meinwald will demonstrate Xen, a popular server virtualization system. He will give some background, including the difference between paravirtualization and full machine virtualization, then will show a demo of creating and administering a virtual machine.</description></item><item><title>This Week in Slashdot</title><link>/events/2010-01-14-this-week-in-slashdot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2010-01-14-this-week-in-slashdot/</guid><description>This Thursday, January 14th, at 7PM in Dreese Labs 266, Alex Lingo will be presenting an old club favorite known as &amp;ldquo;This Week in Slashdot&amp;rdquo;. Slashdot (commonly abbreviated as /.) is a website located at http://slashdot.org that deals in news for the nerdy. Readers submit articles which are then accepted or rejected by editors and then published on the site. From there, the readers have huge discussions about every aspect of the article which can be very funny/interesting/insightful/etc and oft prove to be a very good read.</description></item><item><title>emacs</title><link>/events/2009-12-18-emacs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2009-12-18-emacs/</guid><description>This Thursday, February 25th, I, Professor Ed Overman, a professor in the math department at Ohio State University, will be presenting on emacs in Dreese Labs room 266. I began using an 026 keypunch machine in my student days (which clearly did not need an editor). My first interactive time-sharing experience was using CITRAN (which was commonly known as SHITRAN). My first pleasant time-sharing experience was using TECO (TExt COrrector) and SOS (Son Of Stopgap) on Digital Equipment Corporation computers using a 110 baud interactive teletype machine.</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>/events/2009-12-07-projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2009-12-07-projects/</guid><description>This page aims to be a comprehensive list of projects in progress.
Please email us or leave a comment here if you would like to suggest another project or help with an existing one.
General Meeting ideas Purchase needed hardware. Server Connect email on all machines and VMs. Set up a KDC on Stallman. &amp;lt;s&amp;lt;figure out=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; nss=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; issue=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; on=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; debian=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; and=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; related=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; effects.&amp;lt;=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; s=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;— done&amp;lt;/s Kerberize LDAP, NFS, rest of VMs.</description></item><item><title>Vim!</title><link>/events/2009-11-17-vim/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2009-11-17-vim/</guid><description>This Thursday November 19th, 2009, at 7PM in Dreese Labs room 266, Daniel Thau will be giving a presentation on how to wield the mighty power of Vim. He will give an overview of the history, origin and explanation of vim, a brief comparison to Emacs, as well as basic and advanced usage of Vim. Some of the features he will be presenting include q-recording, window splitting/tabs/buffers, advanced copy/paste buffers, line completion, some cool ex commands, and other more advanced stuff most people don&amp;rsquo;t know/use.</description></item><item><title>Linux Install Fest</title><link>/events/2009-11-04-linux-install-fest/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2009-11-04-linux-install-fest/</guid><description>For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know, Microsoft had (is having) a Windows 7 install fest. On November 5, 2009 after our regularly scheduled meeting The Open Source Club will likewise be hosting an Install-Fest of free, open source software. This is rather last minute, but you won&amp;rsquo;t be disappointed if you show up! We are giving away free and open-source applications and operating systems. Plus if you are really eager to getting the software or even an operating system on your laptop we will be gladly installing them for you.</description></item><item><title>10/22/2009 - All About Python</title><link>/events/2009-10-11-10-22-2009-all-about-python/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2009-10-11-10-22-2009-all-about-python/</guid><description>On Thursday October 22nd, 2009, in Dreese Labs 266, Michael Yanovich and Brian Kennedy will be presenting to the club on the programming language Python. Michael will be demonstrating the basics of building a Python program, beginning with a Hello World in the interpreter and moving over to building Hello World as a stand-a-lone file. Then, he&amp;rsquo;ll cover functions, documentation, and linking files together. Then, Brian will be demonstrating how to use Python to solve problems for class, work, and research as well as teaching the basic use of some powerful scientific and mathematical tools collected in the SciPy module.</description></item><item><title>General Lightning Talks</title><link>/events/2009-10-11-12-3-2009-general-lightning-talks/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2009-10-11-12-3-2009-general-lightning-talks/</guid><description>On Thursday December 3rd, 2009, we will be hosting another lightning talk session that will be compromised of subjects coming from all areas. Lightning talks will consist of several different presentations by different presenters over the course of the meeting time. We will put more info on here about how long the meeting will last and how many presentations there will be once we get more info on who wants to present on what topics.</description></item><item><title>Linux Kernel Configuration</title><link>/events/2009-10-11-10-29-2009-linux-kernel-configuration/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2009-10-11-10-29-2009-linux-kernel-configuration/</guid><description>On Thursday October 29th, 2009, at 7PM in Dreese Labs room 266, we will be presenting on how to configure the Linux kernel. If you have ever been lost when trying to compile or make menuconfig just confused you so much that you wanted to pull your hair out, then this meeting is for you. A few of our members will be making a collaborative effort on this topic so bring your questions to us and we will do our best to help.</description></item><item><title>Mobile Software Development Forum</title><link>/events/2009-10-11-11-12-2009-mobile-software-development-forum/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2009-10-11-11-12-2009-mobile-software-development-forum/</guid><description>On Thursday November 12th, 2009, we will be hosting a discussion on the merits, ideologies, pros, cons, and whatever else that can be discussed about mobile software development. WebKit, Android, Midp, and etc are all fair game for discussion so bring your questions, rants, and raves to the meeting so we can all have a nice old fashioned forum discussion.</description></item><item><title>Source Control Lightning Talks</title><link>/events/2009-10-11-11-5-2009-source-control-lightning-talks/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2009-10-11-11-5-2009-source-control-lightning-talks/</guid><description>On Thursday November 5th, 2009, we will be holding a lightning talk session on a multitude of different source control programs. Lightning talks will consist of several different presentations by different presenters over the course of the meeting time. We will put more info on here about how long the meeting will last and how many presentations there will be once we get more info on who wants to present on what topics.</description></item><item><title>Scott Merrill from Columbus FreeGeek</title><link>/events/2009-10-09-scott-merrill-from-columbus-freegeek/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2009-10-09-scott-merrill-from-columbus-freegeek/</guid><description>On Thursday October 15th, 2009, Scott Merrill from Columbus FreeGeek presented on how to get involved in the tech scene here in Columbus. FreeGeek Columbus provides computers and training for limited-resource populations in Central Ohio through redistribution of used equipment and the use of Free Software. FreeGeek Columbus is committed to Free Software, responsible electronics recycling, and community engagement. In his presentation, Scott gave us a brief overview of who FreeGeek is and what they do, touch upon the hazards of electronic waste, describe how FreeGeek rewards volunteers, and share how they&amp;rsquo;re advocating Ubuntu Linux to people.</description></item><item><title>LVM In A Nutshell</title><link>/events/2009-10-07-10-8-2009-lvm-in-a-nutshell/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2009-10-07-10-8-2009-lvm-in-a-nutshell/</guid><description>This Thursday at 7pm in Dreese Labs 266, Alex Lingo, a former President and Vice President of the club, will be presenting on the much misunderstood topic of LVM. The Logical Volume Manager is a system in the Linux kernel that allows the abstraction of physical data volumes into so called &amp;ldquo;logical volumes&amp;rdquo;. For example, with LVM, 3 1TB disks can be combined into a single 3TB linear volume. Alex is going to give a brief overview of how the system works, as well as give a demonstration first hand to show the ins and outs of the system.</description></item><item><title>Open Source Club IRC Rules</title><link>/events/2009-10-07-open-source-club-irc-rules/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2009-10-07-open-source-club-irc-rules/</guid><description>Rules for OSU Open Source Club IRC Channel
Throughout these rules “our”, “us,” and “we” will refer to The Open Source Club at The Ohio State University. Also the following: “your,” “you,” and “yours” will refer to anyone logged into the channel whether they are or are not a member of the club.
All information and instructions given within our channel are to be used at your own risk. By following or using any of this information you give up the right to hold us liable for any damages.</description></item><item><title>Intro to Linux and an Overview of Distros</title><link>/events/2009-09-28-10-1-2009-intro-to-linux-and-an-overview-of-distros/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2009-09-28-10-1-2009-intro-to-linux-and-an-overview-of-distros/</guid><description>This week Alek will be giving an introduction to Linux and an overview a good chunk of the Linux distributions that one has to choose from. We will go over all the pros, cons, features, strengths, setup nuances, requirements, and finally how to pick the perfect distro for your needs. After the overview we will then run through a graphical install of Ubuntu and then a text based install of Debian in order to both show the differences between the distributions and how text and graphical installs differ.</description></item><item><title>First Meeting of the Year</title><link>/events/2009-09-21-9-24-2009-first-meeting-of-the-year/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2009-09-21-9-24-2009-first-meeting-of-the-year/</guid><description>This Thursday, in Dreese Labs room 266, we had our first meeting of the 2009/2010 school year. We have many things to do at this meeting, including drafting/revising the constitution, and discussing meeting topics for this quarter. Please note: We are located in Dreese Labs room 266. This is not in the main part of Dreese, and easily confused with Baker Systems and Engineering. The room is near the bridge connecting Dreese and Baker, and to the west.</description></item><item><title>Welcome to Torvalds!</title><link>/events/2009-08-04-welcome-to-torvalds/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2009-08-04-welcome-to-torvalds/</guid><description>Welcome to our new server, Torvalds. Everything should be as it was on the old website (as of 8/4/09) except for a newer, hopefully less buggy version of Drupal. Enjoy!</description></item><item><title>Revising the Constitution</title><link>/events/2009-05-31-revising-the-constitution/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2009-05-31-revising-the-constitution/</guid><description>This Thursday, June 4th, the Open Source Club leaders for the 2009-2010 school year will be discussing changes for the following year. All club members are strongly encouraged to use this opportunity to give their feedback about how the next year should be run.
First on the list is revising the constitution. Members can register/login and post their views/concerns/opinions about the constitution and potential changes in the forum thread located here.</description></item><item><title>Updating the Constitution</title><link>/events/2009-05-29-updating-the-constitution/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2009-05-29-updating-the-constitution/</guid><description>This Thursday, June 4th, we are reviewing and revising the club constitution, as well as working out the logistics of what we will be doing in the next year. Please come ready to offer feedback. Also, as of today the website is open for commenting. Please post any ideas about changes you have on the constitution page. Registration required.</description></item><item><title>2009-2010 Elections</title><link>/events/2009-05-24-2009-2010-elections/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2009-05-24-2009-2010-elections/</guid><description>This Thursday (May 28th), in Dreese Labs room 317, we elected club officers for the 2009-2010 year.
Those who ran for an officer position are listed below. Active members were only allowed to run for one position, And members were required to attend for their vote to be counted. Only full-time students who will be enrolled full-time at OSU were allowed to apply.</description></item><item><title>Embedded Control for Art &amp; Music</title><link>/events/2009-05-15-embedded-control-for-art-and-music/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2009-05-15-embedded-control-for-art-and-music/</guid><description>On Tuesday May 19th, Embedded designer, musician, and ex-Imagineer Jamie Robertson will be giving a talk on embedded systems in the art and entertainment world.
Jamie recently collaborated with Mike Gordan, a member of the band Phish, to create an interactive multimedia installation which was part of the 2009 Boston Cyberarts Festival. For this project, he designed, built, and programmed a wireless, distributed, people-sensing system capable of playing sounds and controlling lights based on proximity to works of art.</description></item><item><title>Computer Vision &amp; Robotics</title><link>/events/2009-04-24-computer-vision-and-robotics/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2009-04-24-computer-vision-and-robotics/</guid><description>This Thursday, Robotics guru Scott Preston will show us how to engineer and program mobile robots with web cameras for vision and microcontrollers for communicating with onboard sensors, all from an Ubuntu PC.
The meeting will be held in Dreese Labs room 113 at 7:00.
Scott Preston is a member of the Java Community Process, Central Ohio Java Users Group, Columbus Ruby Brigade and founder of The Columbus Robotics Society. He wrote his first book The Definitive Guide to Building Java Robots, by Apress in 2005, and Co-Authored, Real-World- Ajax by SYS-CON Media in 2006.</description></item><item><title>Advanced Bash Scripting</title><link>/events/2009-04-19-advanced-bash-scripting-04-23-09/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2009-04-19-advanced-bash-scripting-04-23-09/</guid><description>This Thursday, 4/23/09, Tom Henretty came to show us some more advanced bash techniques. Tom demonstrated some of the stuff that Jim Dinan didn&amp;rsquo;t have time to get to back when he did his awesome bash talk in December.
A tentative outline for this event was:
Shell tools / techniques
IO redirection / piping (with basic grep, awk, and sed)
Flow control in bash - (if, for, tests)</description></item><item><title>Intro to Python</title><link>/events/2009-04-13-intro-to-python-4-16-09/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2009-04-13-intro-to-python-4-16-09/</guid><description>This Thursday, April 16th, Catherine Devlin will be giving us an introduction to the Python programming language.
This presentation is a quick introduction to Python programming using a live graphical demonstration. A simulation of solar system dynamics is built in gradual steps, with Python concepts and syntax demonstrated as we go. This presentation is suitable for anyone who&amp;rsquo;d like to get started with Python, or who just likes seeing planets blow up.</description></item><item><title>Effective sshd_config</title><link>/events/2009-04-09-effective-sshd_config-04-09-09/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2009-04-09-effective-sshd_config-04-09-09/</guid><description>This Thursday, April 9th, in Dreese 317 , Alek Rollyson will be giving a talk on how to secure your shell server through effective configuration.
Tricks will include:
Disable root login Public/private keys Disable X11 forwarding Login attempts/timeout Only allow certain usersnames to login Only allow certain groups to login Interaction with PAM Allow by ip address Block by ip address</description></item><item><title>Club Stuff</title><link>/events/2009-04-01-club-stuff-04-02-09/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2009-04-01-club-stuff-04-02-09/</guid><description>This Thursday [04/02/09] we will be giving an overview of to expect this quarter.
Topic that will be discusses are:
Upcoming events Future meeting topics Elections for next years officers You will also have a chance to suggest:
Meeting topics How we spend the money we got from e-council Possible events we can attend as a club As always, the meeting will be at 7p in Dreese 266.</description></item><item><title>SSH tunneling, TOR, proxies, etc.</title><link>/events/2009-03-04-ssh-tunneling-tor-proxies-etc-3-5-09/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2009-03-04-ssh-tunneling-tor-proxies-etc-3-5-09/</guid><description>This Thursday [3/5/09], brought to you by Alek Rollyson, we talked about certain important internet related topics. How does one go to work without leaving his house? How does one completely mask himself to the internet? How does one hide his traffic from even his own ISP? All of these are accomplished by what we discussed. Specifically we talked about (and covered to some extent):
Internet privacy, the cute little paradox SSH Tunneling How (and why) to use DD-WRT for a nice little SSH tunnel Proxies: TOR, SOCKS, etc.</description></item><item><title>Wifi Hacking</title><link>/events/2009-02-21-wifi-hacking-2-26-09/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2009-02-21-wifi-hacking-2-26-09/</guid><description>This Thursday [2/26], Alek will be showing us how to hack into a wifi network.
Topics covered will be:
Overview of why you would want to hack wifi Hacking tools What WEP is and how it works, flaws etc How to hack WEP Overview of what WPA/WPA2 is and how it works, flaws etc How to Hack WPA/WPA2 Man-in-the-middle attacks [if time allows] By the end of this meeting you&amp;rsquo;ll have the wisdom needed to go out and break into wireless networks&amp;hellip;.</description></item><item><title>Xbox 360 Modding</title><link>/events/2009-02-18-xbox-360-modding-2-19-09/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2009-02-18-xbox-360-modding-2-19-09/</guid><description>This Thursday [2/19/09] we&amp;rsquo;ll be taking apart an Xbox 360 and looking at its insides. I&amp;rsquo;ll also be showing how I did some mods to make my Xbox look a little sexier. By the end of this meeting you&amp;rsquo;ll have all the knowledge you need to go home and void your warranty!
As always, the meeting will be at 7pm in Dreese 266.</description></item><item><title>Doing it Live</title><link>/events/2009-02-12-doing-it-live-2-12-09/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2009-02-12-doing-it-live-2-12-09/</guid><description>This Thursday [2/12/09] we are going to just do-it-live and see where the topic ends up going. All of our best meetings seem to be the ones where we get sidetracked and start talking about random stuff&amp;hellip; so why fight it?
As always the meeting will be at 7pm in 266 Dreese.</description></item><item><title>Project Stuff</title><link>/events/2009-02-05-project-stuff-2-5-09/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2009-02-05-project-stuff-2-5-09/</guid><description>Tonight (Thursday, 2/5 ) we will be doing the impossible and making more forward progress on a club project. There will also be some people from the design college coming to talk about projects they need help with, so while they are there we will milk some ideas for an interface from them.
For those who missed our last project meeting, here a quick recap:
We will be working on making a desktop widget.</description></item><item><title>Open Discussion</title><link>/events/2009-01-15-open-discussion-1-15-09/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2009-01-15-open-discussion-1-15-09/</guid><description>Due to the bad weather we have chosen to postpone our original meeting topic for this week. There will however still be a meeting for anyone who wants to come hang out. We will be letting people suggest future topics that they would like to see (or present). As usual, the meeting will be at 7p in Dreese Labs 266.</description></item><item><title>Involvement Fair</title><link>/events/2009-01-08-involvement-fair/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2009-01-08-involvement-fair/</guid><description>The Open Source Club is going to be at the 2009 Winter Involvement Fair in the lobby of Knowlton Hall this Thursday [1/8]. Therefor there will be no meeting this week. But feel free to stop by the involvement fair if you want to chat with us!</description></item><item><title>Wireless hacking</title><link>/events/2009-01-07-wireless-hacking/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2009-01-07-wireless-hacking/</guid><description>This Thursday, January 7th, at 7PM in Dreese Labs room 266, we are doing a talk and demonstration on hacking wireless networks. There will be 3 parts to the discussion. First, Brian Swaney will be talking about the dangers of poor security. He will go over why wireless communication is inherently insecure, what types of attacks are possible on wireless networks, some techniques common people use to try and secure their networks, and why they ultimately fail.</description></item><item><title>Shell scripting</title><link>/events/2008-12-04-shell-scripting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2008-12-04-shell-scripting/</guid><description>Fun and merriment has ensued during this week&amp;rsquo;s meeting as we explored scripting, hacking, and otherwise misusing the Unix shell with Jim Dinan. Topic were focused on bash, and included:
Comparison of different shells The Linux file system, links, inodes, and file pwnership Input/Output between files and commands Variable setting, referencing, and changing Executing commands and files (with proper permissions) Here are some of the slides used, courtesy of the Arctic Region Supercomputing Center:</description></item><item><title>This Week in Slashdot</title><link>/events/2008-11-20-this-week-in-slashdot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2008-11-20-this-week-in-slashdot/</guid><description>This Thursday, November 20th, for the first time in over a year, Alex is doing This Week in Slashdot. Prior knowledge of Slashdot or familiarity with current events are not required. Random discussion is encouraged. Meeting location is Dreese Labs room 266.</description></item><item><title>OpenVPN</title><link>/events/2008-11-13-openvpn/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2008-11-13-openvpn/</guid><description>This Thursday (November 13th), Alex is presenting on OpenVPN and how to set up a simple OpenVPN client/server connection. As usual, the meeting is at 7:00 pm in Dreese Labs room 266.</description></item><item><title>Interface Design</title><link>/events/2008-11-06-interface-design/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2008-11-06-interface-design/</guid><description>This Thursday we will be having a guest speaker come in and teach us about interface design. The speaker will be Matthew Stanford, who is currently working on his masters degree over in the design department. You may think that design isn&amp;rsquo;t important, but I have learned from experience that your really awesome code will go unnoticed if you don&amp;rsquo;t have a nice interface to go with it. I urge you to come if you can because this is a very important presentation that will help everyone make their work more presentable.</description></item><item><title>Meeting</title><link>/events/2008-10-23-meeting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2008-10-23-meeting/</guid><description>We are having a club meeting this Thursday [10/23/08] at 7:00p in Dreese 266. Due to the the fact that everyone is really busy this week we are unsure if there will be any presentation given.</description></item><item><title>Wiimote Hacking</title><link>/events/2008-10-23-wiimote-hacking/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2008-10-23-wiimote-hacking/</guid><description>This Thursday we will be taking a look at the Nintendo Wii remote (or Wiimote) and giving a brief overview of how it works. After that we will look at some of the Wiimote hacks that have been done by other people and hopefully come up with an idea for a new hack that we can start working on as a club project. We will be meeting at 7pm in Dreese Labs room 266.</description></item><item><title>Critical Analysis of Respondus LockDown Web Browser</title><link>/events/2008-10-17-critical-analysis-of-respondus-lockdown-web-browser/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2008-10-17-critical-analysis-of-respondus-lockdown-web-browser/</guid><description>This past year, the Carmen team got a new program for all of us to use. The catch is, it sucks, and your instructors can hold your grade in the balance if you don&amp;rsquo;t play with their new toy1. The program is inappropriately called &amp;ldquo;Respondus LockDown Browser,&amp;rdquo; and it&amp;rsquo;s supposed to be the next generation of &amp;ldquo;secure&amp;rdquo; test taking. While I passionately despise those who earn their marks unduly by plagiarism/forgery/exam-shoulder-surfing, this program is invasive and outright stupid.</description></item><item><title>Source Control Management</title><link>/events/2008-10-16-source-control-management/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2008-10-16-source-control-management/</guid><description>This Thursday&amp;rsquo;s meeting (October 16thin Dreese Labs, room 266) will include a presentation on source control management. The main tool that will be used is Mercurial, however most of what is shown can be applied to many of the other source control management tools. When you are working by yourself on really small programs, like the ones you do in CSE 221,222,321, then you can get away with not using any source control tools.</description></item><item><title>Ohio Linux Fest</title><link>/events/2008-10-11-ohio-linux-fest/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2008-10-11-ohio-linux-fest/</guid><description>The Open Source Club is going together to the Ohio Linuxfest this year on Saturday, October 11th. The first presentation is at 9:30 am. Rather than drive/taxi, bring your Buck-IDtmand you can ride COTA for free&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Linux</title><link>/events/2008-10-02-introduction-to-linux/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2008-10-02-introduction-to-linux/</guid><description>This Thursday, at 7:00 pm in Dreese Labs room 266, we will run through an introduction to Linux, in a way that any computer user - new or veteran - can understand. Some basic points to be discussed are:
What is Linux? What does Linux do? Why is Linux better than Windows (or why not)? Who does Linux appeal to? What are some of the advantages/disadvantages of using Linux? What features does Linux have?</description></item><item><title>Welcome Week Introductions</title><link>/events/2008-09-25-welcome-week-introductions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2008-09-25-welcome-week-introductions/</guid><description>We have scheduled a meeting for Thursday, September 25th at 7:00 pm in Dreese Labs room 266. There is no official meeting topic as we will spend the time doing introductions (trying to be sociable or something to that extent). Meetings are open to everyone as always, so please stop by.</description></item><item><title>Net Neutrality</title><link>/events/2008-09-08-net-neutrality/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2008-09-08-net-neutrality/</guid><description>This Thursday (October 9th) in Dreese Labs room 266, I am presenting on Net Neutrality. See a summary of what I&amp;rsquo;m presenting below.
Key Points:
Net Neutrality is a principle, that if passed into law would prevent internet service providers from using their control over your internet connection for anything other than serving you. It prevents ISPs from blocking/degrading access to competitors' (or any) websites for commercial or political reasons.</description></item><item><title>Website problems</title><link>/events/2008-06-07-website-problems/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2008-06-07-website-problems/</guid><description>We are currently having some problems with our content managing system, Drupal, so changes here will be limited. We apologize for the inconvenience, and a group of us are working hard on the issue, despite limitations such as not having physical access to our server. We expect to have the site fully functional by the end of this summer, possibly with some great new features for active members. We are planning a great number of projects this year (some of which may be aided by our server), more than we&amp;rsquo;ve had for a long time.</description></item><item><title>Code Version Managment</title><link>/events/2008-04-10-code-version-managment/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2008-04-10-code-version-managment/</guid><description>We are meeting Thursday, April 10th, at 7:00 in Dreese Labs room 266. The topic for our meeting is source code version control, and what works best for, and there has already been much traffic over this on our mailing list. Subtopics so far include bitkeeper, cvs, git, Google Code, Mercurial, svn, trac, and open discussion of any other source code management programs not yet mentioned that deserve recognition.</description></item><item><title>Spring 2008 - First Meeting</title><link>/events/2008-03-27-spring-2008-first-meeting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2008-03-27-spring-2008-first-meeting/</guid><description>We had our first meeting for the quarter in Dreese Labs room 266 at 7:00 pm. Meetings end whenever they end, with no specific time. No absolute topic was decided on, so we discussed a few random things, such as South Park creators Trey Parker and Matt Stone streaming South Park online for free (where we legally watched a recent episode from Season 12, which does play in Linux without DRM hacks), Adobe creating a web-based free express (and watered down) version of Photoshop, we also spent a few minutes sharing our web-development views.</description></item><item><title>Hacking the Wiimote</title><link>/events/2008-03-03-hacking-the-wiimote/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2008-03-03-hacking-the-wiimote/</guid><description>Last week, we had a really good turnout and watched some demos of hacking the Nintendo Wii remote to create your own virtual 3-D environment in relative to your perspective, along with a few other slick multi-touch-screen interfaces, bordering on making keyboards obsolete. We had a really great turnout and are considering doing it in the future. More information is yet to come&amp;hellip; There is also some talk about hacking the new Eee, a $500 child-sized laptop similar to the OX (One Laptop per Child campaign) with Linux pre-installed that, for the price, has some pretty impressive hardware specs, and I might add it is very light-weight.</description></item><item><title>Silverstripe Meeting Tonight</title><link>/events/2008-02-28-silverstripe-meeting-tonight/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2008-02-28-silverstripe-meeting-tonight/</guid><description>We are meeting tonight (Thursday, February 28th) at 6:00 pm in Scott Lab room 103. Please note that this is not the normal time/location we meet. We are meeting one hour before our normal meeting time, and in Scott Lab instead of Dreese Lab. Our guest speaker, Jim Muir, is a nuclear and mechanical engineering who had better write solid code, and this presentation could be volatile, so we can just let Scott Labs bear this one.</description></item><item><title>Forums are back online!</title><link>/events/2008-01-24-forums-are-back-online/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2008-01-24-forums-are-back-online/</guid><description>After months of returning error messages to users who went to opensource.cse.ohio-state.edu/forum, the Open Source Club forums are back online. This past summer, p0rn and pharmaceutical spammers had a field day, then our website got taken offline and we had to disable forums and comments. We have cleaned up some lingering spam comments, re-enabled the forum, and added a captcha requirement in order for anyone to log in, as well as a few other random things.</description></item><item><title>Student Involvement Fair 2006 Photos</title><link>/events/2008-01-19-student-involvement-fair-2006-photos/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2008-01-19-student-involvement-fair-2006-photos/</guid><description>A couple of weeks ago we attended the Student Involvement Fair and had a blast. Here are some photographs of the event courtesy of Peter.</description></item><item><title>Google Android</title><link>/events/2007-11-15-google-android/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2007-11-15-google-android/</guid><description>Our last meeting (Nov 15) was about the Open Handset Alliance&amp;rsquo;s Android. A mobile operation system and application stack. We had a demo with the Hello World and spent a lot of the time playing with the emulator prototype. Because I feel this is a very interesting development, I personally will be working on creating some apps for the platform. In addition, Google has $10M in prizes for developers who create interesting new applications for this platform.</description></item><item><title>Open Source Elections</title><link>/events/2007-05-16-open-source-elections/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2007-05-16-open-source-elections/</guid><description>The Open Source Club at The Ohio State University (OSSOSU) will be holding officer elections to represent us for the next (07-08) school year. The eligibility requirements for being an officer are that you are a student at Ohio State, and that you are a member of the club (have attended at least one meeting). Graduate and undergraduates are both equals in this matter.
Open Positions: Benevolent Dictator, Number Two, and Treasurer</description></item><item><title>Crashing Windows Vista Launch Party</title><link>/events/2007-04-17-crashing-windows-vista-launch-party/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2007-04-17-crashing-windows-vista-launch-party/</guid><description>On April 17th2007, with about a couple hours' notice, some of us gathered for an hour before the meeting to join the fun at Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Windows Vista launch party in Dreese Labs.</description></item><item><title>Mailing Lists</title><link>/events/2007-01-25-mailing-lists/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2007-01-25-mailing-lists/</guid><description>We have two mailing lists: A discussion mailing list and an announcements-only mailing list. Announcements are sent to both so you will most likely want to subscribe only to one or the other. If you are in the department of CS&amp;amp;E at OSU you can also participate on the discussion list via the cse.opensource newsgroup:
OpenSource Discussion OpenSource Announce</description></item><item><title>Meetings: Winter 2007</title><link>/events/2007-01-25-meetings-winter-2007/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2007-01-25-meetings-winter-2007/</guid><description>We are meeting Tuesday evenings this quarter at 7:00pm in Dreese Labs room 480. Meetings generally last about an hour and are always open to the public including nonmembers and nonstudents. For people arriving from off campus, pay parking is available in the Tuttle Park Place Parking Garage, located adjacent to Dreese Labs. Please refer the OSU map for directions: osu.edu/map.
01/09/2007 - Up and Blogging with Wordpress in 5 Minutes (Alex Lingo) 01/16/2007 - Contributing to Open Source (Paul Betts) 01/23/2007 - Free Piza Chat Fest 01/30/2007 - Impress your Friends with LaTeX (Jim Dinan) 02/06/2007 - Cancelled (Snow) 02/13/2007 - Cancelled (Snow .</description></item><item><title>Up and Blogging with Wordpress in 5 Minutes</title><link>/events/2007-01-08-up-and-blogging-with-wordpress-in-5-minutes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2007-01-08-up-and-blogging-with-wordpress-in-5-minutes/</guid><description>Wordpress is a powerful open-source blog publishing platform.It is highly customizable with a powerful theming system and many available plugins. In this meeting I will show how to install, set up, and manage a Wordpress installation. The talk will also cover Wordpress theming and plugins.</description></item><item><title>Virtualization Session</title><link>/events/2006-11-02-virtualization-session/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2006-11-02-virtualization-session/</guid><description>A big thanks to everyone who made it to today&amp;rsquo;s meeting on Virtualization! We had a great turnout, great discussion and some pretty hillarious demos!
Also, here are some URLs that I promised to post:
Xen Project at University of Cambridge XenSource Home Page (very cool flash demo here) XenSource LiveCD (used for today&amp;rsquo;s demo) Xen Documentation Xen and the Art of Virtualization</description></item><item><title>The Internet is Burning...</title><link>/events/2006-10-25-the-internet-is-burning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2006-10-25-the-internet-is-burning/</guid><description>&amp;hellip;atleast our mailing list has caught fire.
Who would have thought &amp;ldquo;Linux vs. Windows&amp;rdquo; would have drawn any attention? I just want to rehash a comment made during our latest meeting &amp;ldquo;This week in slashdot&amp;rdquo; where +5 points was awarded for mentioning that &amp;ldquo;the Internet is not a drug&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;
I believe there was a joke in there, something about doing something for coke&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Net Neutrality Debate : 5 Oct 2006</title><link>/events/2006-10-16-net-neutrality-debate-5-oct-2006/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2006-10-16-net-neutrality-debate-5-oct-2006/</guid><description>A dual perspective approach to the Net Neutrality debate. Think of it as driving on the highway and you can go 60mph for a regular rate, or 80mph at a more expensive rate. Everyone is in favor of being able to pay more to go faster, but net neutrality adds that the guy at 60 should be able to go everywhere that the guy at 80 can go without additional charges.</description></item><item><title>Ohio LinuxFest 2006</title><link>/events/2006-09-30-ohio-linuxfest-2006/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2006-09-30-ohio-linuxfest-2006/</guid><description>On September 30, 2006 Ohio LinuxFest 2006 will occur at the Greater Columbus Convention Center. This event will draw over a dozen sponsors, twenty speakers, and nearly two-thousand attendees.
The Open Source Club is proud to once again play a part in an event which began on The Ohio State University campus. As a .org level sponsor, we will be attending and manning our own booth this year. We will draw up plans for our booth once the date draws closer.</description></item><item><title>PulseAudio with Paul Betts</title><link>/events/2006-09-26-pulseaudio-with-paul-betts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2006-09-26-pulseaudio-with-paul-betts/</guid><description>Room: 480 Dreese Labs
Paul gave a great presentation on PulseAudio, the new sound server that will officially make its debut in GNOME 2.18. As a special treat, Alex gave a preview of Peter&amp;rsquo;s upcoming Net Neutrality meeting, explaining that the Internet is not a dump truck, but really a series of tubes.</description></item><item><title>Avast, me hearties!</title><link>/events/2006-09-21-avast-me-hearties/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2006-09-21-avast-me-hearties/</guid><description/></item><item><title>New Drupal-based website launched</title><link>/events/2006-09-21-new-drupal-based-website-launched/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2006-09-21-new-drupal-based-website-launched/</guid><description>Months ago I made the decision to use Microwiki as the base of our website, replacing the old HTML site that we had previously. At around the same time, Freegeek Columbus switched from MediaWiki - the software that drives Wikipedia - to Mircowiki, and they seemed happy enough. It seemed a good choice for us. I thought that we should use something small and simple. Microwiki, weighing in at just 163 kilobytes, is undoubtably small and simple.</description></item><item><title>Welcome Back with Alex! / Ideas for Ohio LinuxFest</title><link>/events/2006-09-21-welcome-back-with-alex-ideas-for-ohio-linuxfest/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2006-09-21-welcome-back-with-alex-ideas-for-ohio-linuxfest/</guid><description>Date: 09/21/2006 Time: 7:00PM Room: 480 Dreese Labs
Welcome back for the 2006-2007 school year! Come and find out what we are planning for this year for the Opensource Club and share your thoughts and ideas. Would you like to see less talk and more rock? Then come and voice your opinion! We are especially interesting in your ideas for the upcoming Ohio LinuxFest 2006. Linuxfest is a free conference of over a dozen open-source sponsors and twenty speakers, all celebrating the greatness that in Linux and open source.</description></item><item><title>Welcome Back!</title><link>/events/2006-09-21-welcome-back/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2006-09-21-welcome-back/</guid><description>Hello all, I hope everyone had a great summer and is ready for the next quarter of the Opensource Club to begin! We have a couple of important events occurring within the first few weeks of the quarter I&amp;rsquo;d like to talk a bit about, since they are new and exciting.
The Opensource Club will be taking part in the Student Involvement Fair on September 18th. We will have a table in the Technology section of the fair.</description></item><item><title>Updated: Student Involvement Fair/Ohio LinuxFest pamphlet</title><link>/events/2006-09-10-updated-student-involvement-fair-ohio-linuxfest-pamphlet/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/events/2006-09-10-updated-student-involvement-fair-ohio-linuxfest-pamphlet/</guid><description>As part of our participation in the Student Involvement Fair and Ohio LinuxFest 2006 I&amp;rsquo;d like to hand out pamphets that showcase who we are and our upcoming meetings. I&amp;rsquo;ve started work on it, and would appriciate any idea or comments you may have on it. You can download it at the bottom of the page in OpenDocument and PDF formats. Edit: The automatic uploader is not working, due to possible SELinux issues.</description></item></channel></rss>